Easwaran Jayaraman: Hello, good evening, everyone.
germayne: Good evening, good evening.
Soon | NTU: Good evening.
germayne: Love the… love the energy.
germayne: We can start off the week strong, right?
germayne: Okay, hope everyone feels good.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Yes?
germayne: Okay, you guys can see the screen, right?
Lik Hong Eng: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, so I think we will just get started in one minute's time.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so good, good evening, good evening, everyone.
germayne: So this is the last… 4 lessons from…
germayne: me, right? Before you guys sort of move on to the next module.
germayne: So what we're going to be talking about today is specifically what we call neural networks, and also what people call deep learning. And what will happen is that 3.7 would serve as the foundation for you to really, really understand some of the latest
germayne: you know, advancement in AI to some extent, right?
germayne: We… we are not there yet, but at least for the last couple of weeks.
germayne: from 3.1 to 3.6, we have some sort of idea on, you know, all the various mathematics and all the various algorithms when people think about. So, neural network, I will take some time today to really build the foundation.
germayne: And, of course, today we will focus a bit more on the theoretical aspects, rather than on the code itself.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so you can see from 3.1, 3.2, 3.3, 3.4, and 3.5, we sort of really talk about supervised learning and unsupervised learning, correct?
germayne: So what will happen today is we will go back to supervised learning, because neural network, at least for today, we're going to learn what the building blocks of neural network consist of, and how does it really come into the goal of supervised learning.
germayne: And this will really be the first step in, you know, getting some basic foundation to understand exactly what are some of the latest leap in advancement that we have today.
germayne: Okay, so today we'll talk about 3.7. 3.8, we would, based off what we have learned today, right, think about it from a computer vision standpoint.
germayne: Okay, so today we will have the foundation of deep learning and neural networks. 3.8, we will see how this is actually applied to solve computer vision. And by the way, neural networks are actually not fundamentally new, which you will see today.
germayne: And then, of course, 3.9 next week, and 3.10, we will go a bit into NLP. And then when we think about NLP, that's when we start to think about, you know, some of the basics.
germayne: And, of course, NLP has existed way long before the hype in large language model. And then, naturally, in 3.10, we would talk a bit about the
germayne: architecture of the large language model. Of course, there's no way we can cover everything. It is a… it is a field that is changing non-stop. DeepSig just released, like, a couple of days back. So.
germayne: Instead, what you really want is to have the foundation to think about how these algorithms come about, and understand how it works, okay? And so that when things keep advancing, you have the foundation to get yourself up to speed.
germayne: Okay, so for today, right, the objective is to really understand the basics for neural networks, right? It's really, really the building blocks, okay? And of course, from the coding perspective, the applied
germayne: application will be using PyTorch as a library, right? But I can really assure you that if your foundation for PyTorch… if your foundation for neural networks is super, super, super strong.
germayne: using the library will just be super easy, right? So, that would be my advice. Hence, I think we'll talk a bit more on the theory side, rather than to… rather than on the code.
germayne: Okay, so you can see today's lesson is a bit… is a bit… is going to be a bit packed, right? We'll first talk a bit about gradient descent.
germayne: Right? I'll introduce what gradient descent is, and it is a very important
germayne: foundation in all of the neural networks, as well as all the latest algorithms. Without written descent, none of this will exist, right? Of course, we have some introductions on neural network. What exactly is this neural network that people is talking about? And we'll talk a bit about Perceptron and MLP, which is the basic form of… the easiest form of neural networks.
germayne: So if you were to take Andrew Erng's deep learning specialization, the pedagogy will be similar. He will introduce MLP as the basic building blocks before you can even think about computer vision.
germayne: I'll talk a bit about the components of neural network. We'll balance a bit with the math, right? If you really cannot understand the math, I think it's okay. But if you can appreciate it, fantastic.
germayne: Right? Of course, we'll, you know, talk a bit about the loss functions, because as you can see now, every model requires some kind of understanding of the loss function, because it's the direction of how we define that the model is learning, correct? So at this phase, you sort of understand that when people talk about AI models, there's nothing
germayne: magical. Everything is just math under the hood. You just realize that we are just basically doing math computation. And loss function, again, is just a way for us to direct what is correct or what is bad.
germayne: We'll talk a bit about the forward and backward, which is essentially how does a neural network actually processes your prediction, and how does it actually learns using backward, which is backward propagation.
germayne: Okay, so when people… when you heard about, oh, we know people talking about backward propagation? We'll talk about it today.
germayne: I will give a bit of math, but if you are very, very interested, you can explore the math in your own free time. And then finally, we will then apply this from an application standpoint on the toy dataset, which is the digit data set, the MNIST dataset, as well as on the Titanic dataset.
germayne: Okay, so we have a lot to cover today.
germayne: So, I think let's get started.
germayne: Okay, so I want to talk a bit first about gradient descent, right? So gradient descent is really the important building block when it comes to a neural network, okay?
germayne: So what exactly is gradient descent?
germayne: You can think of gradient descent as a form of optimization, where it essentially needs a few criterias, right? So the first criteria here is that gradient descent first requires your function to be differentiable.
germayne: Okay, and I think you guys start to see a trend here, right? That, actually, we require certain strict constraint on the function to be differentiable. What does differentiable mean? It means that the functions can be differentiated. There are functions, there are metrics that cannot be differentiated directly.
germayne: But if a loss or a function can be defined to be different shape… differentiable, then, of course, gradient descent will work, okay? And we will have a bit of visualizations later. So one very good example is, you guys have been always seeing your mean square error loss. Mean square error, if you look at the equation.
germayne: let's say you have Y minus,
germayne: Okay, let me, let me just…
germayne: So, for example, this is your mean square error. You can obviously see that this, if let's say, this is a function f, I can always differentiate this. I can always find the differential, if I do a different… a first order differentiation, I can always differentiate this.
germayne: Okay? It's okay if you don't have… can't remember how to do differentiation, it doesn't matter. The point here, I'm just trying to show is that for any given function, if it can be… if there is a derivative, we can apply gradient descent, so that is the first criteria.
germayne: Okay? And the second criteria that we will see from gradient descent is that, given any parameter, okay, I'm going to
germayne: make some small change here. So if, let's say, again, just for the sake of our… let me just remove this, huh? So now, instead of talking about MSC, let's just talk about a very generic function.
germayne: Let's suppose our function that we are interested today is called X squared. Obviously, we know that when you differentiate x squared, it's just going to be 2X, correct?
germayne: So, what gradient descent tells us for criteria number 2 is that, given any differentiable function, if I were to update the stat towards its gradient, I will always be able to find the X that minimizes the F.
germayne: Okay, so what this means is that if I were to update X, I can start X anywhere, but if I were to update X,
germayne: So I'm going to call it XT, which is, like, the next time step, but if I take the previous time step of X,
germayne: and I move it towards the gradient, which is DF over DX. Okay, let me… let me move the equation somewhere.
germayne: So, criteria number 2 basically tells me that
germayne: if I can update X,
germayne: where X I can start at a random point, and if I will continuously update X towards the direction of a gradient, I'm always going to find X, I'm going to find X,
germayne: Such that I can minimize.
germayne: F.
germayne: So if… so now the intuition that you guys get to see is that, what exactly does this actually tells us, right?
germayne: Forget about the fancy math.
germayne: The criteria here is number one. If there's a function that's differentiable, and number two.
germayne: For any given point, if I can update a point on the function towards the gradient of the function, I can always find that point such that I minimize the function. So you notice the idea here is that in machine learning, we all along want our algorithm to minimize. We want to make sure the loss is always small.
germayne: Correct? We have repeatedly seen this across the whole module, so it's not, like, something new. You guys know that we always want some kind of metric.
germayne: And that's how we always define whether the model is learning. And we want to define the objective that we are interested in as the loss, and what we want is we always want to find some kind of parameters that minimize the loss, which means that I have a model that's actually good at solving the problem that I want. And that's actually how gradient descent is being applied.
germayne: Okay? I'm going to interchange this.
germayne: I'm going to show you something that I prepared.
germayne: And I want you guys to just look at my screen here.
germayne: You guys can see my screen, right? So in this, in this example, what we are just trying to show is that if I were to start on any… and of course, of course, by the way, because this is a very simple function, we know that obviously the minimum point is at 0 for X squared.
germayne: Correct? This is a known function. But the idea here, I'm telling you, is that we know that
germayne: from our eyeball, and of course from calculation, and of course from differentiation, we know that the lowest point of the function X squared is 0. There's nothing that can go smaller
germayne: for FF equals to X squared, right? 0 must be the smallest. So the idea here is that I can find X equals to 0 by starting anywhere on the graph. And in here, what I'm going to do is I'm just going to choose a random… so I'm going to start at
germayne: 6.7… oh, wait, so I'm just starting on a random point on the curve here. So you can see here, we are just starting at 3.395.
germayne: what I'm going to do is I'm going to iterate X, right? I'm going to iterate X by using gradient descent, which is the equation that I've shown, by updating X towards the gradient, towards the negative gradient of X squared. So, as you can see, the next point will be
germayne: 2.6876.
germayne: And you notice that X is constantly going smaller and smaller.
germayne: Right? You can see, right, X is going smaller and smaller, smaller and very, very small.
germayne: And you can see that eventually the correct answer for X to converge must be 0, because that's the lowest point, right? If I go all the way, you can see X eventually converge.
germayne: So the idea here is that if we are able to formulate and find a loss that is differentiable, and of course one… and of course.
germayne: for regression, regression problems, we saw that we always, most of the time, use mean square error. That's not the only one, but mean square error is differentiable. So what this means is that we can apply gradient descent in order to update our parameters, in order to find the parameter such that it minimizes the loss.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: All clear? So, a take-home exercise for you is, you know, this is the… this is the… the formula to do gradient descent is like that.
germayne: It's in the notes.
germayne: Oh, sorry,
germayne: So the, the formula to do gradient descent, of course, there's a, there's a, there's a, there's a, there's a factor here, a learning rate factor.
germayne: There's of course a learning rate factor here, but the idea here is that you can try this as a take-home exercise. You can initialize X to be any big value.
germayne: Right? And if you were to move and update X bit by bit towards the gradient of the function, eventually X would converge.
germayne: to zero.
germayne: Right? So, you can work this out in order to understand gradient descent, but in my perspective, this is the easiest way to understand gradient descent. So, from an optimization perspective, we can basically make use of this property
germayne: For training neural networks.
germayne: Okay, then now, I want to ask you guys a question.
germayne: So, very early on in our lesson, we learned about OLS, right, the ordinary least square for regression. I want to ask you guys.
germayne: Do you think I can use gradient descent to find the parameters for OLS?
germayne: For my linear regression.
germayne: Basically, in my linear regression, I define my parameters to be all of the better.
germayne: Can I use gradient descent?
germayne: to find data, what do you guys think?
germayne: Do you think it's possible?
germayne: Some people say yes.
germayne: Right? Because exactly what I said, right? Given some parameters, we can always find, and of course, your objective, right? Your objective is going to mean the mean square error.
germayne: And the function is going to be something like that. It's going to be a loss. We take in the Y, and of course, we take in all of the beta
germayne: Just to be clear.
germayne: So basically, these are the ones that we can control. We can always find beta 0 all the way to beta n, such that the mean square error is
germayne: You know, converge, or minimize.
germayne: So, naturally, you'll realize that, oh, actually, we can use gradient descent.
germayne: Which leads to the next slide. So, of course, you know, this equation here is just to tell you that the way that OLS is done today is that there is an analytical equation. By doing this equation, you will always be guaranteed to minimize mean square error, right?
germayne: That is from an analytical standpoint. But with gradient descent, we can actually use it to find the parameters, right, such that it will converge. And you'll notice the values will be very, very similar.
germayne: Okay? So that is the power of gradient descent.
germayne: Okay, I will, I will, I will pause here first. Anybody…
germayne: has any questions before I go on for gradient descent. So this is part one. We are done with part one. So part one is, understand what gradient descent is.
germayne: Anybody has any questions so far?
germayne: Okay, so Gwen, you are saying in the… can… can I assume… the Delta Greens.
germayne: What was the delta grid? Sorry.
germayne: You want to explain, Gwen?
germayne: Oh…
germayne: So you are saying that, can we assume that the delta to make the RMSE score less than 21.2? What does that mean?
germayne: Is the question more of, like, does it mean that I can always use gradient descent to find the lowest error? Is that the question?
germayne: There's a question, right? What do you guys think?
germayne: So, so, that's actually a very fantastic question. So, Jermaine is saying that
germayne: If the… oh, and actually, I missed out one more criteria.
germayne: Actually, one of the criteria is that, the… the loss function needs to have a concave shape. So, obviously, here you can see that there's a minimum here, right? So…
germayne: The question here to me is that, okay, if I'm able to use gradient descent, shouldn't I be able to find the perfect loss?
germayne: So what do you guys think from an intuition standpoint? Before I give the answer.
germayne: Does it mean that if I have gradient descent, it means that I can find the parameter to make sure that my loss is zero, is perfect?
germayne: What's the… what's the first intuition that you guys have? Do you think that's correct?
germayne: Do you think that with gradient descent, we can always find the parameter such that the loss is at minimum, which is zero?
germayne: Is that possible?
germayne: Does that sound correct?
germayne: Now, from a… from a… without giving the answer, but from a empirical standpoint, what do you guys think? From an empirical standpoint? Which means, based on what you guys have tried in Kaggle.
germayne: What do you guys feel? Is it possible to get zero?
germayne: No, right?
germayne: And the answer here is because… Notice ingredient descent?
germayne: What we are saying is, when we do gradient descent, of course, in this very easy example on the left.
germayne: what is the parameter of the function here? The parameter is X.
germayne: Correct?
germayne: Okay, you can see the parameter here is X, right? In your typical… in your typical loss function, what is happening is that your loss
germayne: Again, right, because mean square error and root mean square error is monotonic, so it doesn't really matter, I can just talk about mean square error. You know that mean square error is your Y minus Y hat.
germayne: Right, this is your function. Now, if I expand this formula.
germayne: What you're predicting here is going to be some kind of parameters that you find.
germayne: Correct? So there's some kind of function.
germayne: If you use some complex model, or whatever model that you're using, let's say you are using neural networks, you have some kind of parameter, or whatever, whatever model, you have some kind of parameter W here.
germayne: You'll notice that later on, you will see that actually what you are trying to find is W.
germayne: So, this function here is not concave.
germayne: Right? The function is only concave if it's with respect to Y hat. But we are not finding the best y-hat. We are finding the best W, so that we can predict Y-hat.
germayne: So what this actually means is that you cannot see the loss function, but
germayne: It's going to be very complex.
germayne: And there might be multiple local minimal.
germayne: So, which means, from a function standpoint, you might find the best here.
germayne: But is it the best globally? It might not be the best. It might be the best from a local minimal standpoint.
germayne: Right? So that is the intuition, because you're optimizing not with respect to the main parameter, in this case here is Y hat, you're always finding a parameter
germayne: Your function is always optimizing some kind of parameter W.
germayne: W can be your beta if, in linear regression, in neural networks can be your weights, right?
germayne: In other models, like, your decision trees can basically be your trees.
germayne: Right? If you're using XGBoost, it's basically all your weak learners. It's basically your W.
germayne: Right? And this is not necessarily an immediate concave function with an extreme minimal
germayne: Right? Which is what we call the global… the global minimal.
germayne: Right? Of course, if everybody can find a global minimal, my job will be very easy, right? Every model that I train will just work.
germayne: Okay, so that is the intuition here.
germayne: Alright.
germayne: Okay, I want to move on.
germayne: Okay, so now I think, towards the… towards the end of the module, I will give you guys a full summary mind map, but you… essentially, you can start to see here that when people talk about artificial intelligence.
germayne: On one hand, it's a term that is very easy to get investments, or a very easy-to-sell term, but artificial intelligence has never been just about large language model. It has always been more than that. And from a computer science standpoint.
germayne: even things like robotics, or even some of the classical algorithms, have actually been thought of in terms of artificial intelligence. What has been… what has taken off is actually more of machine learning, right? Which you guys have actually sort of learned in the previous few lessons, right?
germayne: And neural networks today is a kind of subset of machine learning.
germayne: Right? Where we are going to learn more on the supervised portion. Most of the time it's used for supervised, it can be used for unsupervised, right? Not saying that it's only for supervised, but today we are talking more about from a supervised standpoint.
germayne: And of course, deep learning is again another subset where you have a different architecture.
germayne: And today, you will see, like, what makes neural network complex is what makes it powerful, and makes it difficult to be applied.
germayne: Right? And of course, when you think about generative AI, it's really just a very, very…
germayne: subcategory of deep learning applied on NLP, which is natural language processing. Understanding of text data, and how does the model actually predicts what is the text that's going to be outputted.
germayne: So essentially, your large language model is just doing supervised learning.
germayne: All the time, when you're asking questions.
germayne: Okay? So today, right, what we are going to do is that we are going to go back to supervised learning.
germayne: Okay? So, again, to set the direction for supervised learning, you guys have previously learned that, you know, what we are trying to do with supervised learning is you have a target label.
germayne: You want to learn some kind of mapping function, f of x.
germayne: Such that I can predict Y hat.
germayne: Right? The objective of supervised learning is to learn F of X. That's what you guys have learned, right? In linear regression.
germayne: If you guys remember, we talked about a very basic, you know, Shumin mentioned something about the line and the slope.
germayne: If you guys remember.
germayne: Right? So today, what we are going to do is we are going to expand this
germayne: formula to make it even more complex. We're essentially saying that we are going to learn
germayne: some kind of function, which takes in X,
germayne: takes in W, and we are trying to learn what W is.
germayne: And essentially, you will see that it's just W,
germayne: dot X plus B, from a linear standpoint, right? You will see that
germayne: From a neural network perspective, we can actually not just generalize a linear model, a linear regression, a logistic regression, but in fact, we can make the model more complex. And again, what's the goal? The goal is to learn the weights.
germayne: From a neural network standpoint.
germayne: Okay? So, which is why when you start to see that people are saying that, oh man.
germayne: Today, I have a new model from Alibaba, right? I'm open sourcing some kind of weights.
germayne: Right? People always talk about weights, right? From a large language model standpoint, you'll notice that W actually stands for weights.
germayne: Essentially, the model's parameters is W.
germayne: And these weights is what define the model.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: And of course, you can see that deep learning is used everywhere, right? At this point in time, almost everything is done in deep learning, right? You can see here that Uber uses ETA, uses deep learning to predict ETA, and of course, part of my job is to also build models to predict very accurate ETA.
germayne: Okay? And, you know, you'll see things like your medical devices, image segmentation, image classification, we will see on Thursday, right? And of course, your large language model is all based on deep learning.
germayne: Okay, so from a very interesting standpoint, a very interesting backstory, actually neural networks was kind of created because, you know, we kind of want to follow the structure of the human brain. You will see that actually everything can be expressed in math later on.
germayne: But the idea here is that you think of each of these individual layers as neurons, right? And what we want to do is we just want to pass, and we want to architect, right? Think of neural networks like Lego blocks.
germayne: Now, the expressive power comes from the fact that you can define the different LEGO blocks.
germayne: If you think about LEGO blocks on its own, each LEGO block is useless. It's very small, right? Just a square.
germayne: But when you put all the LEGO blocks together, you have something very impressive to express something. So, same thing as the neural network. You realize today that what we are trying to learn are very basic fundamental math using matrix algebra, using linear algebra.
germayne: And each of these components, you can think of them as Lego blocks, That now you can build.
germayne: you have the ability to build all kinds of complex neural networks, which could allow you to have some kind of expressive power, right? But then now then you can start to see that what makes this
germayne: The superpower also makes it challenging to build.
germayne: Because now you are trying to build a LEGO block, unlike the previous machine learning algorithm, where the algorithm is already defined. Now, you not just have to tweak the knobs
germayne: Of the parameters. Now you need to decide how to build the neural network.
germayne: And you can see this is complex, right? Who can build a neural network? There's so many degrees of freedom, how do I know what is right?
germayne: Right? If you're thinking of that. And of course, that makes it difficult to use neural network, unless you are in the research team, where you are able to define that. So in practice.
germayne: People don't really build their neural network, usually we base it off some kind of architecture that somebody has created.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: And of course, deep learning is just a subset of the term. The category of algorithms are just all neural networks, but deep learning just basically means that we are just building an architecture of a neural network so big and so deep that we just call it deep learning.
germayne: Okay? And then you have your deep neural networks, are just basically the same, but just that we build it, you know, just like your LEGO blocks now, your LEGO blocks is just insanely deep.
germayne: insanely big.
germayne: And then we can also do it for CNN, convolutional neural networks, which we will see on Thursday.
germayne: We'll talk a bit about recurring neural networks on next week.
germayne: Right? And essentially, the idea here is that neural networks are done in a way where it has a specific bias to the type of data that you are using.
germayne: And you'll start to see that when people create neural network, there's some kind of intuition which matches with the data.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So it's really, really super good at handling unstructured data, right? You notice the word here, unstructured.
germayne: Right? What this basically means is that if your data typically is structured.
germayne: Traditional machine learning algorithm still works.
germayne: Right? So it's not saying that, oh, just because deep learning now is
germayne: better, more expressive, it just means that all the algo that we learned is useless. Because 99% of the problem that deals with structured data still uses all the algorithms that you learned previously.
germayne: It is only things like images, audio.
germayne: text data, obviously text is basically your LLM.
germayne: Right? These, you can obviously see that it has been dominated using deep learning.
germayne: Okay? And in the subsequent lessons, we will give the… I will give the intuition why it works so well on unstructured data. Okay? And it's because of this thing called the inductive bias.
germayne: Okay? Because the neural network
germayne: It's like a Lego block that allows you to build all sorts of crazy architectures. You essentially can build an architecture that allows you to capture the bias of the data. Essentially, what is the data's intuition and information that you want to capture, you can actually build it using a neural network.
germayne: So you can see that, this is really just typical illustration, right? You can basically see that this is really just a 3-block neural network, and of course, in the deep learning space, you can have, you know, n numbers of blocks, right? Of course, the deeper
germayne: The more nonlinear that you introduce, which we will see later on, right, the deeper the model, the more nonlinear layers you add, the more expressive the model becomes.
germayne: But then, what do you guys think about when the model is very complex and very expressive? What happens?
germayne: Does it mean that I'm saying that the deeper it is, the better?
germayne: Can I sing it?
germayne: Why? Why is it that the deeper it is, it might not be better? What's the intuition that comes to your mind?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: over 15.
Josiah Ho: complex.
germayne: Exactly, exactly. So basically, your model just becomes so good at just memorizing the data, because the model is just overly complicated.
germayne: So, how to define the architecture? It becomes both an art, as well as mostly just following what people have built, from a research standpoint. Unless you are a researcher that builds neural networks, there's no way that you can come up with a neural network that all of the sudden will be the best in the world.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So obviously, right, as I mentioned, neural networks has existed, you know, very long ago. If you look at all of the textbooks.
germayne: the MLP that we are talking about, right? Essentially, the Perceptron model has been around… they call it Perceptron back then, you know, it undergoes so many changes in the name, right? But back then, all of the models, all of the math has always existed. Textbook.
germayne: 10, 30 years ago, they already have this concept. It only became more popular because of, number one, right? Why is it that data science became very popular? Because, number one, we have an explosion of data, right? As you guys can see from a data engineering module that we did.
germayne: Right? There's a lot of data right now. From an application standpoint, from a mobile phone standpoint. There's so many touchpoints which you can use the data to train a model.
germayne: Number two, hardware.
germayne: Right? That is also the reason why GPU now is super expensive, and that is the reason why Nvidia stock trades at $200 plus USD.
germayne: Right? In just 5 years ago, NVIDIA stock is, like, 20, 20 USD.
germayne: Right?
germayne: So GPU, obviously the backbone needed to train neural networks, because each of the math computation requires some kind of vectorization, some kind of, you know, GPU in order to do the computation fast.
germayne: And of course, we have the last, which is more of open-source software, where now we are, you know, living in a, at least for the last 10 years.
germayne: Working on open source.
germayne: you know, software that people has created, right, where the community is maintaining, look at all of your libraries that you are doing, these are all open source. So all of these dynamics makes all of these algorithms so much more powerful as compared to maybe 10 to 20 years ago.
germayne: Alright.
germayne: Okay, I'm going to go a bit faster here. Deep learning, obviously, anything that's unstructured now works super well. Things like computer vision, right? Image detection, I'm sure you guys known of these, right?
germayne: You have things like your NLP. We can obviously see today the application for this is large language models. But again, this has existed long ago. I've been doing NLP since 2017, right? When it's not even that popular, right? Speech recognition, I think I told you guys about the Kaggle competition that I did.
germayne: You can detect birds, right? And actually, what people do is actually just a computer vision problem, right? Of course, you can see all of these are essentially where, deep learning has sort of dominated, right?
germayne: Again, the caveat here is not saying that every algorithm requires deep learning, right? And you will start to see why.
germayne: Because to make a fast inference for deep learning, you need GPUs, right? But are GPUs accessible? Maybe not.
germayne: Okay? So, there are still some drawbacks in deep learning. And of course, I think today, I can safely say that it doesn't dominate in tabular data.
germayne: Alright.
germayne: Okay, so you can see a bit here. I don't think I completely agree with this, but of course, the idea here is that, you know, in traditional machine learning, I always emphasize to you guys that, you know, feature engineering is, like, key.
germayne: The algorithm is, like, maybe 10% of the effort.
germayne: 90% of the effort here is on feature engineering. I'm not sure whether you guys agree, after you did the Kaggle, will you guys agree that feature engineering actually is the bulk of the time? The algo is, like, just click a button, right? I'm sure you guys did that, right? Twick the button, you know, tweak the parameters, you know, it's not difficult. Everybody can run.
germayne: classification model, everybody can run regression model. 90% of the effort is in feature engineering.
germayne: Now, for deep learning, right, theoretically.
germayne: because the model is the model is supposed to know how to encode the data spaces, actually the model, by right, you know, can learn on its own. But by left, you know, by right is like that theory, but by left, actually having good features still matters. It's not like having, you know, they always call it garbage in, garbage out, right? You put nonsense in.
germayne: Why would a model learn something new? So, the input data still matters.
germayne: But I think what deep learning is trying to say is that, you know, for, like, the top 1% of people, if you're able to create some kind of crazy architecture to leverage the data, then maybe you don't need to do feature engineering.
germayne: But for, like, 99% of the cases, especially for very simple models, right, I'm not talking about unstructured, I'm talking about structured data.
germayne: If you're talking about structured data.
germayne: Feature engineering is always present, even if you use a neural network. For unstructured data, things like your image and stuff.
germayne: image, audio, NLP, you realize that actually you don't need to do that. Because in the past, in 2017,
germayne: when I did NALP, basically, we have to do a lot of feature engineering. But now, fast forward to 2025, nobody does feature engineering anymore, if you're using any of the
germayne: neural network architectures for NLP, okay?
germayne: So this is very, very true for unstructured data, but again, if you're using structured data, I can tell you that 99% of the problem is still solved by XGBoost and LightGBM.
germayne: Okay? So it doesn't mean that neural network dominates every single thing.
germayne: Okay, so I'm sure you guys already experienced feature engineering, maybe you guys are even the expert now, right? After the… after the house pricing. Maybe, we will get to see that on Saturday, okay, when you guys share the… share the learnings.
germayne: Okay, I want to give a pause here first.
germayne: Right? For me to catch my breath, but anybody has any questions so far?
germayne: Shit forward.
germayne: Any questions in terms of, like, how does this reconcile with the previous topics?
germayne: I'll give a pause here while I drink some water.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Actually, I want to ask, How… how…
Chieh Cheng Lai: Well, how do we charge? How well we do the teacher engineering?
Chieh Cheng Lai: For… I mean, just how you mentioned, for the deep learning, not everything we need to do features, features extraction, but how… how… how much level we need to do that one, you know, in order to see, oh, this is good enough for the… for the model.
germayne: Good question, good question. Actually, the… this answer, right, can be answered by all of your experience in Kaggle. You guys realize that sometimes there's no… there's no rulebook, right? You just try certain hypotheses, you see whether it works.
germayne: Right? Of course, if you are an expert in the domain area, where you know that this signal will definitely affect the target variable, then you need to engineer it. But to… back to your… back to your answer, right, Kendra?
germayne: There's no answer, it's an up.
germayne: Right? What kind of features?
germayne: you already have the… the… you are already taught how to evaluate, how to iterate. But if your question is, how do I know when to stop? The answer is you don't know. It's an art.
germayne: That is the… that is why it's hard.
germayne: Right?
germayne: Does that… does that answer? Does that make sense? You already have the tool to know, to test out, to iterate. But what I'm trying to go about here is that there is no hard and fast rule to tell you that, okay, this is enough, this number of features is enough. Nobody knows whether it's enough, because when you change the data set.
germayne: the input changes, everything changes. What worked for you for this dataset? Let's say today, you guys learned that whatever that works for your house pricing.
germayne: If you are changing to a different problem that is not house pricing, whatever that you learn, you can throw into the dustbin. I mean, I'm exaggerating lah. You will take away with some learnings, but it can't be that, oh, I tested this thing and it worked very well for my housing data set. It's definitely going to work for a different dataset. Unfortunately, it won't.
germayne: It will just change.
germayne: So, you still have some learnings, but you're still back to the iteration, you know, to the experimentation perspective. Because otherwise, right, I can draw every model that I built by now, I built so many models, but right, my model now should be perfect already, correct? But unfortunately, it is a new data that I have not seen.
germayne: I need to test out. I need to read some papers to understand what has people tested.
germayne: Understand?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Okay, so it depends on the situation. Because sometimes I get the,
Chieh Cheng Lai: the… the R-square. The R-square, sometimes hit, 93, 95, and then sometimes it hit, lower, maybe,
Chieh Cheng Lai: 77. So I'm wondering, is my feature selected correctly, or my model is something sports wrong?
germayne: So I think, I believe I mentioned that R-square is not the reliable metric, right? What is the way to validate? I think you've been taught, right? How to validate your data, your prediction.
germayne: Correct?
Chieh Cheng Lai: the rooming sway.
germayne: Exactly. So that should be the gold standard to know, it's not just from the R-square.
germayne: Okay?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Okay, okay, thanks.
Hitesh shah: From a layman's term, if deep learning can do even feature extraction and all.
Hitesh shah: In the long run, do you see only deep learning existing and no machine learning?
germayne: No, Hitesh, I can confidently say, because deep learning has been existing since I even started my career, I have also tried using it.
germayne: As of now, for structured data.
germayne: Deep learning doesn't prove that it's better.
germayne: And you will start to see this in the subsequent modules, where there is a specific reason why people design deep learning, there is a specific architecture that is done to handle certain specific behavior of the unstructured data. Hence, it works very well for unstructured data. But for structured data.
germayne: Because we're looking at tabular data.
germayne: Deep learning does not guarantee that it's dominating it. And again, you will start to see later on, end of the day, all these are about trade-offs. I already mentioned to you guys, all these are all about trade-offs, right? Deep learning.
germayne: Has very complex
germayne: experimentation lifecycle. Firstly, you do not know what works if it's a structured data. Secondly, it requires a GPU to predict.
germayne: If you can solve your problem using classical, traditional machine learning, do you want to do deep learning?
germayne: Why? Why should you do deep learning, right? So again, it should go back down to why do you want to do something? Has it been proven to do something right?
germayne: Correct? So, I can tell you that at least as of now, 20th of April 2026, it has been 10 years, and it's very clear that neural networks does not dominate the structured data space.
germayne: But for unstructured data, yes, you can see that everywhere is doing deep learning, alright?
germayne: So, whatever that you learn is still relevant. Of course, if some genius come up with a new deep learning architecture in 10 years' time, then maybe my statement doesn't hold true, right? I do not know what's in the future, but so far.
germayne: So far, there's nothing that is changing structured data.
germayne: Alright.
germayne: So, think… yeah.
Hitesh shah: Yeah, so, so, are there,
Hitesh shah: So, deep learning is a model, for, so, with different organizations, or deep learning is a standard set of algos which is running for everybody's common?
germayne: No, no, deep learning, you will see later on, is like, are like Lego blocks.
germayne: Where you have to build the logo yourself.
germayne: So everybody can have very different deep learning architecture. If it's not published on a paper, nobody will know what kind of secret architecture you have.
germayne: Because the degree of freedom is so huge.
germayne: Right? If, let's say, 5 of you guys were to do this in Kaggle, if you guys don't refer to anything, and you try to build your own, there'll be 5 different variations of your deep learning model. That's how complex it is, right? Everybody will have its own comp… think of it like LEGO blocks. You might not use the same blocks, right?
germayne: Some might choose to use, like, 5 blocks for the hit.
germayne: 6 blocks for the body, right? Expressive power is very good.
germayne: But… Very complex to build.
germayne: So what this means is that
germayne: If you're thinking about feature engineering, you don't even know what features to build. Now.
germayne: your deep learning model is going to take up another 50% of your effort for uncertainty. You do not even know whether what kind of architecture will work, unless you follow a research paper.
germayne: Okay, and that is a reality.
germayne: Alright.
Hitesh shah: So it is still discretionary. Even deep learning will be different for each individual. I mean, it's not like a set of a… I mean, standard set of box, which will be common for everybody, not like…
germayne: No, it won't. I mean, there's a lot of foundation that you guys are learning. Okay, so I like to use this thing called degree of freedom, right? So just imagine if you've got a machinery.
germayne: If you have one button, your job is to only press that one button. Your degree of freedom is only one, right? I can only do one changes. Now, if you've got another knob here, you've got two, right?
germayne: So, what I always express off is, you guys realize that when you do your kegel, each algorithm basically has a series of knobs. It's like you're controlling an aircraft.
germayne: Right? Why people usually say that, you know, like an aircraft, or driving, oh, the aircraft has a lot of buttons, right? Now, imagine in deep learning, not just you have to deal with the buttons, you have to deal with building the box.
germayne: You know, it's not just the buttons now, you need to think about how do I press the button? Which button is the best?
germayne: You need to think about building the box.
germayne: So, what this means is that…
germayne: Very, very powerful, right? Very customizable.
germayne: But of course, with the thing that is… the more layers to customize, the more complex, because now you have to decide on how to do everything. Oh my god, I need to do so many things already, I need to choose how many K, I need to do feature engineering, I need to optimize my parameters, now I need to build the architecture. So you can see, right? You're just having more and more things to build.
germayne: But what's the… what's the good thing, what's the good thing about this?
germayne: You can express whatever you want to express.
germayne: Right? I think another analogy is.
germayne: if you are in school, when you are little kids, you know, you give kids, like, all the… okay, again, this is an analogy where I'm just giving because I don't have kids, but… but I would imagine if you go out, you see people coloring.
germayne: you know, you're a kid, right? You just want to color, you can color… your job is to just, like, oh, okay, I want to color here, purple.
germayne: Is this more complex than giving a blank canvas for you to draw anything you want?
germayne: Obviously, drawing anything you want is…
germayne: Very expressive, right? You can draw whatever you want.
germayne: But which is more complex?
germayne: Obviously, having the ability to draw whatever you want is more complicated.
germayne: then guided. Because here, you just need to decide what colors, right?
germayne: Similar to your machine learning algorithm, I just need to choose the color to color.
germayne: Now, if you are given, like, a blank canvas, you can draw whatever you want. No one is telling you how to draw it.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Moving on.
germayne: Okay, so I, of course, like to do the math portion.
germayne: Okay, if today you feel like you're not on the mood for the math, it's okay. But the idea here is that, actually, right, I just want to show you guys, when you define a neural network, I'm going to show you guys, right, so the neural network looks something like that.
germayne: Essentially, here you can see that there's three layers. So, like what I'm saying, a neural network, you can think of it like a Lego block, right? So, you can just decide, like, a block, a block here, one block.
germayne: And then in my block, I can decide, like, the number of neurons. So the number of neurons is also a parameter for you.
germayne: Right.
germayne: So let's say I just have a very simple box.
germayne: Right? The circle will make sense later on.
germayne: So the idea here is a neural network allows you to define a very simple box. Of course, this is a very simple box, right? I define three…
germayne: LEGO blocks, and my data… my data is just going to be going in.
germayne: Oh, okay, actually, this is a bad illustration. Let me change this.
germayne: So essentially, just like any neural network… sorry, just like any algorithm.
germayne: you can think of a neural network like a LEGO block. You build a… you build a LEGO block, so here you can see I built two LEGO blocks, right? And…
germayne: you just need to fit your data in, and you will just get a prediction. So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to define X to be 3 by N.
germayne: Okay, so for those of you that don't know what this is, this is basically just the size of the matrix.
germayne: Right? So now we are going back to your linear algebra, basically your matrix. So why is it 3 by N? Because you can imagine that there's 3 features and n number of instants.
germayne: in the context of your VCO flat data.
germayne: right, in the context of your VCO flat data, this basically means that you just want to choose 3 variables. So it can be something like your square feet.
germayne: the story… Is there anyone… is that one variable that you guys can give me from the…
germayne: From the house price, one more variable.
Zac Ang: These kids…
germayne: Distance. Distance to where?
Zac Ang: So, school…
germayne: Wow. So that is Zach's secret feature.
germayne: Okay? So basically, you can see, this is actually very similar to the data set. So let's say you use 3. What is N here? N is basically the number of training data that you have, right? The 100K or whatever, right? So what will happen is you can define the first LEGO block. So this LEGO block, right, the size will be 3x2.
germayne: So essentially, what we are basically just saying here is that we are going to create two neurons in this, and then here, I'm going to create another LEGO block, and then I just define it to be, you know, one neuron.
germayne: Right, so the size is 2x1, okay? One neuron here.
germayne: a 2 neuron, the 3 and the 2 is… you naturally have to do it. I'll show you guys later why, right? And the idea here is that I pull in X, I'm going to get Y, right? Because that's how your machine learning does, right? You put the X into the algo.
germayne: Then you just do .predict, and then the algo just gives you the Y. So it's the same thing here, right? Do a dot predict. So actually, what happens in the neural network, right, is that it's actually just doing a very simple math. It's a bit similar to linear regression, right? We're going to do it very, very simple. So what happens is that when the X goes into the first LEGO block, right here.
germayne: Right? The math is that, okay, we are going to call the output here Z1.
germayne: So Z1, we are going to do… so this is W, so again, right, why I call this W is because this is the parameters, this is the weights.
germayne: Right? It defines
germayne: the brain, the logic of the model. The model is supposed to find a W that's good.
germayne: Right? So what I'm going to do is I'm going to take W, right, and transpose W. Basically, I just change the shape, so it becomes 2x3.
germayne: I do a dot product. I do a… basically, a dot product is that you just multiply… you do this special operation on the matrix. So I take W, multiply by X. It's not multiply R, it's a dot product, right?
germayne: My X is 3 by N.
germayne: So basically, if you do matrix, right, the output Z, right, will be 2 by N.
germayne: You notice… notice something special.
germayne: Your dataset initially has 3 variables, right?
germayne: After I multiply with the first neuron block, now the output becomes 2 by N.
germayne: What, what, what is this? You notice that, shit, the dimension actually shrink.
germayne: So you notice this is actually very powerful, right? From 3, I'm actually able to now shrink my verbal to 2. Okay, I'm omitting a lot of things here, but the idea here is to show you that, okay, now that my verbal is 2 by N,
germayne: The next block, this is again the W, the width, another width, W2.
germayne: Right, I'm going to take Zach.
germayne: I'm going to do a dot product, again with W2.
germayne: So I call it Z2. So the output from here is Z2, right? And what is happening here is W2, right here, I'm putting the shape lah, right? 1x2.
germayne: Z, you know, is 2 by N.
germayne: So the output of Z2, right?
germayne: It's basically 1 by N.
germayne: Wow, you notice something changed again. I still have the same number of sample data, right? You put 100K by 3 at the start, 100K at the end is just like… I can't remember how many training data… Zach, how many rows do you remember in your training data?
germayne: How might, how many do you use?
germayne: 100K, is it?
Zac Ang: I think it's 20… 20K?
germayne: Oh, you used 20KR. Okay, so maybe that's a secret, that's a secret.
germayne: So, basically, the N is just a number of predictions that you have, right? You notice that what is happening at the output
germayne: Actually, at this point, right, in Oak.
germayne: Actually, you notice at this point, right, Z2 is, like, my prediction, right? Isn't it?
germayne: I have… I have… I have a row of…
germayne: 1 by n basically means, right, my data.
germayne: I have n number, and then I have one column here.
germayne: Basically, it's my prediction.
germayne: So you notice that your LEGO blocks, right, and this is just a basic LEGO block, you know, I'm just going very basic.
germayne: you can actually express that just by putting these things in… oh, well, I actually can predict something from a matrix perspective. I'm actually predicting my Z2 is basically my output lah, right?
germayne: And then I'm putting the laws here, because later we'll talk about it. But the idea is that you can build a LEGO block, right, where you just put the data inside, it does the multiplication, and then you can just get any shape that you want. And in this example, the shape is… because I want the prediction to be like that, right?
germayne: So the shape will be like that. The shape will be 2 by, 1 by N. N number of rows by 1 column.
germayne: So basically, what I've just shown you guys is what we call the… the… this is, again, a very simple neural network, but what we just did is what we call the forward propagation. So you just put your data in, the data just flow one direction out.
germayne: Right? The… but forget the… forget the math, right? The idea here is just to tell you that
germayne: Oh, actually, we are able to do some kind of linear regression. This is no different than linear regression, right, if you look at the math. W times X.
germayne: is exactly the same… is exactly the same, where if I put beta 0, beta 1, beta 2, beta 3,
germayne: I multiply by X is the same thing, right? The math is the same.
germayne: But you realize that, oh, wow, I can actually express linear regression like that.
germayne: Right.
germayne: Then you start to see it becomes very, very powerful later on.
germayne: Okay? So I, I, I stop here first.
germayne: Anyone has any questions for me from this first intuition?
germayne: So you realize that the math just works out, right? The number, the shape.
germayne: So, where you guys will need to decide is, of course, you won't be writing this when the code is running. You just need to decide how big the block of W is, and you notice that W I chose to be 2 here.
germayne: Right, I chose 3x2.
germayne: The tree cannot be changed, because the input here depends follow here, but the 2 is an engine knob that I need to choose.
germayne: Hey, Jimin, can it be 1,000? Yeah, it can be a thousand, it can be a thousand and one, it can be 1,005, it can be 2,000, it can be 10,000, it can be 500, it can be 10.
germayne: I don't know, can be anything you want.
germayne: And there's only one option, you know? What about this guy?
germayne: Hey, why you choose one? Is it… should I put more blocks in between? Yeah, you can put more blocks.
germayne: Alright, so you can see it's actually very powerful, right?
germayne: So this is the first… first step.
germayne: I stop here first.
germayne: Is it, is it okay? So far, can follow?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, just so you mentioned that,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: And then, yeah, neural networks, you will go back to supervised learning, but it's actually more about linear regression, right? Not really logistic or whatever.
germayne: Not yet, not yet. We haven't got there yet.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Injustice.
germayne: This is just a start only…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, you start to…
germayne: Later, you start to see, right, I start to give you more LEGO blocks. So, like, you know, when you buy LEGO blocks, right, they got the basic blocks, right? But you also can buy the toy, right, you can buy the men, you can buy… you know, you start to get a lot of things, really.
germayne: understand?
germayne: Yeah, yes, Zach?
Zac Ang: I don't quite get the iteration of… Why multiplying matrixes?
Zac Ang: can give you… Prediction.
Zac Ang: Like, is there some way that I can… intuitionalize this…
germayne: So, the takeaway here, right, is I think forget the math. I think the idea here is that
germayne: Your takeaway should be that you realize that the W actually has some kind of importance in determining the output.
germayne: Agree? You notice that the W's job is just to Get some kind of output.
germayne: W1 and W2's job is to, you know, predict with X, right? So what is actually the point of W? The point of W is that by right, you should find a W that is good.
germayne: Right? And if you think about it from a linear regression standpoint.
germayne: Your parameters are all your coefficients, your slopes, right?
germayne: Your slopes are not magically found, there is something that is done so that the slopes can be found. Same thing for W here, right? When we think about neural networks, the thing that defines… of course, again, right, in the neural network, there's a B also lah, but again, I'm omitting the B.
germayne: But the point here is, I'm telling you guys that when you think about the weeds, right, the width is the brain of the neural network. What makes the neural network good?
germayne: When people releases a large language model, everybody says that, hey, can you give me the weights? Whether if it's closed source or open source, depends on whether you can get the weights, right? Open source models, you can download the weights. It's in your computer, you're basically downloading W. Because with W, I can make the prediction.
germayne: Right?
germayne: I have not talked… I have not talked about how to find the W. Now, I'm just telling you guys that this W, let's pretend that we can find the best W. This W basically allows me to multiply with my input data, and, you know, as it passes through this neural network.
germayne: I basically can get a prediction, this 1 by N prediction. That's the takeaway.
germayne: Does that… does that help?
germayne: Right? So, think of the W as the importance of what defines your model, right?
germayne: Again, right, just to re-re- re-emphasize, can I ask you guys one more thing?
germayne: For linear regression, what are the parameters?
germayne: What are the parameters for linear regression?
germayne: Who knows?
Zac Ang: Beta…
germayne: Exactly, the intercept, as well as the slopes, right?
germayne: Those is what define your linear regression.
germayne: As long as you write down on the paper your beta.
germayne: Right? You go to a different company, you can implement the model, right? That's what it defines.
germayne: Same thing for the neural network.
germayne: The problem with a neural network is that you start to realize that W can be very big. You can no longer write down on a piece of paper.
germayne: Right? The matrix here I'm using is very small, but your W can be very big, right? When you think about your large language model, whoa! 200 gigs, 400GB, your W is damn big!
germayne: So your W can be very, very, very big. So no longer you can write it down on paper, but in your linear regression, you can write it down on paper, right?
germayne: So, the W is what defines the neural network. Now.
germayne: The takeaway here is, we know that W is important.
germayne: Right? You cannot change the X, you can only change the W. So what this means is that I can always find a W. I want to find W.
germayne: Such a debt.
germayne: If I multiply then, of course I'm simplifying this, I get…
germayne: Good prediction. That's the goal, right? Because W is what defines the model.
germayne: We'll talk about how to find a W later on.
germayne: Okay? So, you do not know how to find a W. You're like, oh, it a W, is it, like, you can give random nonsense? Yes! At the start, because you don't have W, you're just going to put some random values.
germayne: Because I do not know what's the correct W, right? Initialize them randomly.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Towards the end, we'll talk about how to find it. We are just saying… we still don't… we don't know how to find W. And when people talk about training the model, that's where you are actually training the W, right? You want the W to be better and better.
germayne: Okay
germayne: Anybody still confused before I move on? If confused, you need to ask now, because the… the concept will cascade.
germayne: You will add on and add on and add on and add on, and you will start to become more complex.
germayne: But if you don't understand the math, I think it's okay.
germayne: I will give you guys this, this, this shit.
germayne: is really just matrix algebra here, but the takeaway is don't need to do the math. Takeaway is, I just want to show you guys that W is important.
germayne: Okay?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yeah, I have one question. So, the W, every time past, each level, for example, level 1, level 2, it will change, it will change accordingly.
germayne: No, each block will have its own W.
germayne: Each LEGO block will have its own W.
germayne: So the more blocks you put, the more W you need to train. So you can see here is W1, here is W2. You can see my math doesn't overlap. The W is not changing,
germayne: here, right, we are just trying to say that, actually, it takes not just W1 to be good, because
germayne: what I'm doing here is I'm taking W2 and multiply by the output of
germayne: Z1. So W2 cannot be lousy, right? If W2 is lousy, then it doesn't matter already, correct, Kendra?
germayne: So what I'm trying to put here is, in this simple model, this is a two-layer model.
germayne: is defined by W1 and W2.
germayne: you'll start to learn later on in different, you know, as we start to go to Thursday, go to next week, the way to express a W becomes more and more complex. But end of the day, you want the entire block to be good, not just one block.
germayne: Alright.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Oh, okay, I understand. That's the reason you do the multiplication.
germayne: Exactly, exactly. So, the reason I'm doing the multiplication is that from Z1, right, Z1 goes into this block. It's not, no longer X already. X is the start. This is the input.
germayne: Block number 2 doesn't know about X. Block number 2 only sees Z1, which is an output from W1.
germayne: Okay? So you can see, right, you stack each of the blocks, right, each of the blocks.
germayne: Again, right, you start to see the intuition is that each of the blocks start to see something different.
germayne: Because like a conveyor belt, each W's job is different, right? It's just to look at different things.
germayne: Okay?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Okay, thanks.
germayne: Okay, I assume the rest is Easy peasy for the rest.
germayne: Is it? I continue on?
germayne: Or, you guys want a break?
germayne: Need a break or not?
Edwin Yap: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, let's have 5 minutes. Let's do 5 minutes. Let's come back at 8.10.
germayne: Gwen, what's that? Looks delicious.
germayne: Is it like popcorn?
Gwendalynn Lim: It's cereal, because I'm a child.
germayne: Whoa.
germayne: No, then? I think that's good.
Gwendalynn Lim: Is it healthy?
germayne: Depends on what kind of cereal. If it's conflicts.
Gwendalynn Lim: No, this is the… The Kellogg's, the high protein ones.
germayne: Oh, okay. Oh, fantastic. Oh, I didn't know, like, even cereal has high-protein cereal.
Gwendalynn Lim: Yeah, they have high protein, but if it tastes good, it means it's definitely unhealthy.
germayne: Really? Okay.
Gwendalynn Lim: As the general rule what?
germayne: Okay, so for those that feel like the math is too much, right, you can really just keep the math. The math is not… if it works for you, it works for you, but if you don't need it, I think it's fine, right? So it's optional, it's just an option for those that want to go one more additional step.
germayne: Okay?
Gwendalynn Lim: Can you talk a little bit more about the transform? Because you have the symbol, the W transform, right? For Y hat?
germayne: we will… we will… I think we will talk about that later, lah. I think for now, for now, it will add more confusion, but… but let's… let's just talk. I think maybe we can supplement that on Saturday, yeah.
Gwendalynn Lim: Okay.
germayne: Hmm.
germayne: Okay, so a minute more.
germayne: Yeah, it's just to confirm, right, for Kaggle…
germayne: You can only use till everything that was stored until last week.
germayne: Just to confirm.
Gwendalynn Lim: Oh, nowhere!
germayne: No… no deep learning, please.
Gwendalynn Lim: I, yeah.
germayne: No deep learning.
germayne: Okay?
Gwendalynn Lim: Okay.
germayne: Because I… because I think… I think that will… that will… that will cause a huge difference in… in…
germayne: In results, and I think let's just stick to what we learned until last week, okay?
germayne: If you guys… okay, I… I think, if I remember correctly, after the Kaga competition closes, you guys can still continue to submit.
germayne: Okay, but please, please, no deep learning.
germayne: Everything up till last week.
germayne: Last week was 3.6, yes. Unsupervised, you can use it.
germayne: Of course, time series has no value, but if you can somehow make it work, then yes. Okay?
Gwendalynn Lim: Oh, excellent. Okay.
germayne: Let's continue, huh? Okay. Okay, so just to… just to… just to recap what we have talked about for the last 10 minutes was I talk about what we call the components of the neural network. We talk about what is the input layer, the hidden layer, and the output layer. The input layer is basically your X.
germayne: Your hidden layer is basically your weight.
germayne: And then the output layer is just another, another width, so we call it W1 and W2.
germayne: Okay? So…
germayne: This is the component, and essentially what I have shown you guys is how does the model actually calculate the output using an X, right? So if you think about it, machine learning model.
germayne: It's always an X go in.
germayne: Your white head comes out.
germayne: Alright? So, same thing for a neural network. It's just that now you get to define what is the box.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Now, you guys start to realize that, before I talk about activation functions, you guys actually would have the intuition that, hey, Jermaine, actually, right, it feels very similar to linear regression, man, previously. Why would it be very powerful just because I stacked
germayne: two boxes here. And then, if you have that… if you have that intuition, right, that actually this doesn't look very different from linear regression, actually, you are right. Because mathematically, what I just did, again, I feel that this expresses the math, but if you don't want to use the math, I think it's okay. But what we just did, if you realize, is we take W1,
germayne: I do a dot… I do a dot product with X.
germayne: I take the output, I do a dot product with W2, and I say that this is the final output. If you remember here, I say that here the size is N by 1.
germayne: Right? Basically, I have n number of…
germayne: data points, I have one column.
germayne: And then, if you look at the math perspective, right, actually, we can combine W1 and W2, right? W1 multiplied by W2, we just call it W3.
germayne: Hey! Shit, this is linear regression.
germayne: Because if I can always find a W1 and W2 that multiplies together, I can definitely get a W3 that equals to W1 times W2, correct? So actually, I don't need to express them in two blocks.
germayne: Basically, the power of two blocks is the same as the power of one block. That's what I'm trying to show here.
germayne: Correct? Mathematically, right? If there exists a W2 multiplied by a W1, then there must exist a W3 that is exactly the same as W2 and W1. I don't need to express them twice, right? If you look at the math, I'm just multiplying W2 multiplied by W1. So what it's actually trying to say here is that if you have a very deep layer, but everything is linear, you can only learn linear pattern.
germayne: And what's the output of a linear pattern? This is exactly the same as a linear regression, right?
germayne: Right? The expressive is not very strong, though. W3 times X, oh, I'm only doing a straight line. So the idea here is that actually, right, the power of neural networks comes with another… now, you know, now you unlock another LEGO block, which is basically, we can actually apply some kind of transformation called the activation function.
germayne: And this activation function is to actually make the output nonlinear.
germayne: So now… the W's, Are now forced to learn about some nonlinear properties with respect to the data.
germayne: Alright, so that's the intuition here.
germayne: Okay? So now we are going to start to deviate away from linear regression. Okay?
germayne: So, there are, of course, a few activation functions here. You have things like sigmoid.
germayne: I want to ask you guys a question, I'm not sure who is, you know, able to tell me.
germayne: We actually talked about sigmoid.
germayne: Not directly, and we don't call it sigmoid, but we actually talk about it. It's not new.
Zac Ang: Logistic regression.
germayne: Exactly, exactly. This is exactly the logistic mapping, right? Logistic regression's formula is basically like that.
germayne: Basically, this is a logistic regression.
germayne: So, what you realize here is that actually you can… you can really build whatever you want.
germayne: in a neural network. It's very powerful in expressing
germayne: Right? Every linear model, it can be expressed, can even get the same parameters, right?
germayne: So the idea here is that you can start to express
germayne: different activation functions, and of course, each of the activation functions has different property. Here, basically, what you are… what is happening is, if, let's say, I have a LEGO block.
germayne: And I decide to put a sigmoid here.
germayne: What happens is that all the output will be bounded between 0 and 1.
germayne: Anybody wants to know why Y1 are output to be bounded between 0 and 1?
germayne: What am I trying to do here?
Gwendalynn Lim: It's a yes or a no for a decision of confidence.
germayne: So, basically, we want to do subclassification, correct?
germayne: So you start to realize that, oh, wow, okay, so now if I add in sigmoid, I can do classification. If I remove sigmoid, I can do regression, because I can predict continuous value.
germayne: So usually this is actually used as the last layer, usually. More often than not. Usually for a binary classification problem. We call it, I call it BCE.
germayne: Right, okay, sorry, just binary classification.
germayne: Not BC, sorry.
germayne: Right? 10h not very common nowadays. Relu is also another nonlinear property, because you can see that everything that is… so what, what RareLu basically maps is, it takes the max between 0 and X. If your X is in the negative range, it just becomes 0. For anything… so for, for X,
germayne: less than… for X. So basically, if you remember, the equation looks something like that. It's 0.
germayne: 0, if X is less than zero. Otherwise.
germayne: X. So basically, this is the… this is the… this is the stepwise function that you see in the equation. So basically, this is also nonlinear, and actually, ReLU is used very, very common in a lot of architectures, right, in order to induce nonlinearity. Of course, we are not going to go very, very deep, but one property is because ReLU is also very good for the gradient flow.
germayne: Very good for the gradient, which you'll see later.
germayne: Right? And again, you see the word gradient, right? Something should ring in your head. Oh, something to do with gradient descent. Right? That's why I talk about gradient descent at the start of the course, or at the start of the lesson.
germayne: I didn't introduce gradient descent for fun.
germayne: Right? So, ReLU actually also helps in gradient flow. So then there's also leaky ReLU, which is just another variant of ReLU. You can see here there's a slope. So the slope is a parameter. So basically, you want the model to learn about this parameter.
germayne: Right, then there's also ELU. So basically, there's a lot of activation function, more and more, never, we will never ever cover, but ReLU is usually the basic. ReLU, Sigma, these are all the basics, and 10H.
germayne: So these are the basics.
germayne: So the idea here is that you can add in activation functions in order to make the output and the relationship that the model learns to be non-linear, so that we no longer regress to this issue, where no matter how many blocks that you're putting, your output is just linear.
germayne: Okay? So what this means is that you can learn very complex functions.
germayne: And what this also means is that you can start to overfit your model if you're not careful, because it's very powerful, very expressive.
germayne: Okay, so, as I mentioned, sigmoid is typically used for the last layer, right? People tend to use this for… for the, what do you call it? For your classification problem, right? Especially if your output is 1 and 0. Sigmoid allows me to map it to a probability space.
germayne: Right, so it will always be between 0 and 1.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Where do I talk about it already? You guys can read it. The idea, again, is a very effective, non-linear layer, right? Very, very common.
germayne: Right.
germayne: Okay, so actually there's a few guidelines. Again, as I mentioned, the logo block in the middle, usually you want to put ReLU, right? It's just a general rule of thumb.
germayne: How would I know this? Basically, you know, in future, once you guys are really an expert, you guys start to read research paper. Usually, research paper, they would tell you the architecture. If it's open source, you can actually check out how they build it.
germayne: So you will see that ReLU is actually used very, very common, right, to have this hidden layer. You will see on Thursday a lot of the ImageNet models, right? In CB, there's this thing called the ImageNet.
germayne: We'll talk about it, you know, I'll talk about it on Thursday, but basically, these are some models that people use to train computer vision models. You will see that they also use a lot of ReLU.
germayne: Okay, this kind, sigmoid people don't really use it for the linear layer, because it makes the gradient flow super bad, right? You can see that the gradient is actually very bad at, let me, let me check,
germayne: So, for example, your sigmoid, if you look at it here.
germayne: Your sigmoid, right? The intuition here is that the sigmoid's derivative at these two ends actually looks like that.
germayne: Hey, sorry. Sigmoid.
germayne: Sorry, Sigmat, actually, the other slide has it.
germayne: It looks… it looks like… like that.
germayne: So basically, if you look at the derivative here, you will see that this 2N is actually quite bad. It's, like, 0.
germayne: So basically, it has a problem with gradient flow, right? I will talk about why gradient flow is very important later, okay? But the idea here is that, here it's just telling you that here they don't use it because the gradient flow is not good. You will understand why gradient flow is so important later.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, let's, let's continue on. So, so this is just some example of the, of a… this is a, this is, just…
germayne: Okay, this is just a chart to just show you, like, the different, activation function.
germayne: Of course, in practice, I think it depends. ReLU is actually used quite common, leaky value, prelude, there's really too many, right? The whole point here is not to tell you about, like, the whole world of activation. Point here is that activation is important, because you want to have nonlinear
germayne: You want to learn some kind of nonlinear relationship between your X and your Y.
germayne: Right? You don't want it to be linear. Okay? So, you can also see here, we have this, I mentioned sigma is always for binary classification, sigma is also for multi-class, we didn't talk about it, so don't want to avoid some confusion. There's also softmax, and then for regression, you just basically don't do anything, because
germayne: In that example I gave, The N by 1 is actually continuous value.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, I saw that you guys are talking about Mima. You guys are doing Mems.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: This picture is quite good for… to…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: To determine what you want, because you have, like.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Output layer, and all that kind of stuff.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Oh, no, we shouldn't rely on what I just said.
germayne: No, no, this is, this is okay. This is, this is, this is a good summary. This is a, this is a good summary.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: That's how you won, right?
germayne: This one is just a…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Hey, we're backwards.
germayne: This one is just a general guideline, this one not 100%.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
germayne: But the… okay, and I tell you guys why, right? Because for your output, it's always going to be that few classes, okay? Either you do… you do this or do that, so the output layer cannot change much. The input layer, right, the hidden one, right? There are many variations. So these are just some general guidelines, okay?
germayne: But of course.
germayne: Best is just to follow. Best is if somebody implemented, got good results, you try to implement. But just to tell you guys,
germayne: I have… I have always been implementing what people publish in papers. And would you guys want to know that… does it mean that if it's published in paper means it's good? You guys want to make a guess?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Hold on.
germayne: mermaid, I guess? Not true, huh? Not true.
germayne: I have implemented papers, because my job, again, as a data scientist, I'm not doing research. My job is to
germayne: build the model to solve a problem. So I always read papers for specific domains, and see what can be a way to implement it. Sometimes the papers omit certain details, but
germayne: But that's right, the takeaway from the course is that you guys are not supposed to go and, you know, go to a future job, you know, or your future career, and say that you're an expert. You are not an expert at everything. You have the basic foundation, but you should be able to do certain literature reviews, and you should be able to implement a lot of stuff that people have described in published papers.
germayne: Correct?
germayne: So that's usually how it works.
germayne: Okay, I… I will stop here first. Any last… any last questions?
germayne: Huh? I think I saw some memes in the chat, so I think you… I assume you guys are good to go, huh?
germayne: So, Josiah, have you found it?
Josiah Ho: No, I'm still finding my ex.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so we are going to start to go back again, so we talked, so, so far.
germayne: if you think about collecting all your knowledge, we talk about gradient descent, we talk about how to do, you know, how does a neural network actually look like, we talk a bit about how to make it nonlinear. Now, we are going to go back again, right, we are starting to move towards… actually, the goal again is find W, right? How to find W?
germayne: So again, to understand how to find W, we need to go through this guy again.
germayne: Because this guy is a way for us to, you know… because if you say you want to find the best W,
germayne: How do I define best?
germayne: I need a way to measure the best, right? And of course, I need to then measure it using my loss function.
germayne: Come, what are the loss functions that you guys are familiar with?
germayne: This one, CB4?
germayne: See before, right? Seen that many times already.
germayne: Right? So this one also, I think I mentioned, right, min absolute error. Huber loss is basically just a general form of a flexible, function. You can think of it that goes between these two guys. Basically, you can pick a parameter where, if you want it to be very strict, it can become mean absolute error, it can become mean square error, or it can become in-between.
germayne: Okay, so you guys can look up this yourself. Same concept.
germayne: Classification, we didn't really talk too much about it. We talked a lot about the position, recall, if you guys remember, AUC, ROC, blah blah blah. But then, you guys remember I mentioned that these are all not differentiable. How can you differentiate, what, true positive divided by, like, how to differentiate this thing?
germayne: Right? So actually, actually, you know, most of the models that people are using actually just goes back down to cross-entropy.
germayne: Okay? The idea for coarse entropy is actually very simple, okay?
germayne: I need to use the math to express, but just bear with me, okay? So basically, cost entropy, right, mathematically just looks like that. Looks very scary, but it's actually not.
germayne: Okay, I'm just give- I'm gonna give the general form.
germayne: Riah?
germayne: Okay, so you see, alright, the function looks very scary, but actually it's not. Let me show you guys why.
germayne: Okay, so if you look at this function, this function looks very, very scary at first, but…
germayne: You know, if you do… if you look at your mean square error, actually, you realize that this is just the average.
germayne: Average over N. You guys seen this, right? You're just taking the average over N. Then what is this? This is basically your C classes.
germayne: Because in classification, we always want to predict whether 0 or 1.
germayne: But actually, you can expand beyond 0 and 1, you can predict, got cat, got dog, got whatever, so actually you can go to more than that. We never talked about that, but the idea is that we always talk about your C class equals to 2. Binary, right? 1 or 0.
germayne: Correct? Actually, if you look at this function, this, this, this T here, right, basically, right, is looking at the labels where it's a, it's a 1.
germayne: Because if you look at this equation, right, if the labor is a zero, this whole thing is gone. Agree?
germayne: So T is basically the Y.
germayne: So if you remember in your classification, you have your Y, right? So some label is 1, some is 0, some is 0, some is 1, blah blah blah. So you notice here, actually, what we are looking at is we are looking at the T that is equal to 1. The reason for that is we want to predict correctly
germayne: for cases where label is equal to 1. And if you look at this P here, and this log here, right, basically you will see this formula. Basically, what it's telling you is that… can I ask you guys from an intuition standpoint?
germayne: If the label is 1, should the probability be high, or should the probability be small?
Zac Ang: Hi.
germayne: Hi, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: It's wonderful.
germayne: model to predict very big, right? 0.99999 if it's big. So if you plug in the math, right, this is negative, this is log, you realize that
germayne: The laws here will be very small.
germayne: If the probability here is big.
germayne: So the bigger the P, the smaller the loss, because it's negative log P.
germayne: you can go and plug into your calculator negative log 0.9 versus negative log 0.1. So basically, the idea here is just telling you, right, that for classification, this cross entropy is just a way to
germayne: Tell the model that, okay, For cases where, if it's 1, you just output your probability to be big.
germayne: If your probability is small, negative, lot small probability, the loss is going to be very big, which means you're going to get a huge penalty.
germayne: So the model will be like, okay, man, whatever, anything that is 1, I make sure that probability will be as high as possible. I'm trying to push the probability to be as high as possible.
germayne: So that's what the loss is actually doing.
germayne: So, the takeaway here is, right, sometimes don't be so afraid of the map, because the math gives you the insight what they are trying to do.
germayne: Right, so here I'm just telling you that… and intuitively, you know that if it's 1, I want the probability to be… if it's 0, I want the probability to be small.
germayne: How do I put that on paper? I use this cross entropy loss.
germayne: Okay, so basically that's what I'm trying to highlight here.
germayne: just this, right? So basically, takeaway, If… oh, sorry.
germayne: Here, right, it's just that.
germayne: If y equals to 1, my probability Must be big.
germayne: If Y is not 1 equals to 0, probably must be small. That's it. Same thing as your mean square error, right? We talk about, like, oh, if your X is very big.
germayne: wow, you get a huge demerit point, a huge penalty. Then you'll be like, oh my god, I shouldn't do that. I'll be careful.
germayne: Right? So you can see, right, the loss function.
germayne: purpose of this slide is, we still haven't talked about how to find the best W, but we talked about how
germayne: to measure… What is good?
germayne: I'll bet.
germayne: Agreed? The first step to find the best W is to know what is good or bad. Now that we know what is good or bad, we can start to find the best W to tell us whether it's good or bad. Because if I have a direction, then I basically know where to adjust.
germayne: And another fun fact… Because we talk about gradient descent.
germayne: We can now apply gradient descent so that you can find a point on the loss function so that the loss function is small.
germayne: So this provides the guidance, the gradient of this.
germayne: provides a direction, and we're going to use gradient descent, and the missing puzzle here is gradient descent, in order to find the ultimate goal. So when people talk about training model, now you understand, right? Oh.
germayne: Deep learning models all use gradient descent. Deep learning models, you know, use gradient descent in order to find the best W, the best width.
germayne: K… To close the loop for everything.
germayne: This is basically the math that we just did, right? The W…
germayne: Right, this thing. Basically, forward pass.
germayne: If you think about it, right, forward pass, right, is like you've got the Lego blocks.
germayne: Okay, lah, they like to do it opposite, I don't know why. They like to do upwards. You know, you'll think of it as downwards, but they like to do it upwards.
germayne: Okay, so your X, right, go into the Lego block, you do all the matrix multiplication, you get the Y. This is what we call forward pass.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So what does it mean? It means that we assume that all the W's are found.
germayne: Right? Because the W's, once you find it, you don't have to change it, right? You just store it.
germayne: when Alibaba released the large language model, Quen.
germayne: You download it, it's in your computer, right? The weights won't change.
germayne: Correct? No.
germayne: The last piece of the puzzle that we have not talked about, and this is usually where the scary math comes in, is actually called backpropagation.
germayne: So the idea here is we're going to apply backpropagation, we're going to apply gradient descent in order to find
germayne: W.
germayne: Such that… W and X, Minimize L.
germayne: So you realize, right, I'm actually writing English, right? Like, I'm going to find the best W, so that L of W and X will minimize L, because that's the goal, right? I want to find the best loss.
germayne: Just like what you guys are doing, you guys want to find the best model to predict the housing price. The smaller, the better.
germayne: So how do you actually do it?
germayne: Okay, a bit warning here, I'm going to do two intuitions here.
germayne: I'm going to give the very simple intuition, and then I'm just going to do one math.
germayne: Okay, just want math. If you don't want the math, then you listen to the intuition. Don't do the math.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So what is happening here is that when we go through the model, right, just now the one that I did, we're actually doing what we call a forward.
germayne: So basically, everything goes through the thing, gets an output.
germayne: Now, in order to have the signal to update the weights, all your weights are all here, right? W1, W2, if you guys still remember just now. In this case, there's a W3 lah.
germayne: What is happening here, right, is that…
germayne: when you get an output, which is why I had here.
germayne: What do you guys think I will do next?
germayne: So I multiply everything, let's say for the first stage, I take W1, W2.
germayne: W3X. Again, of course, I omit the nonlinearity, right? Let's suppose I never put any nonlinearity, doesn't matter. I get an output Y hat here.
germayne: At this stage, can I evaluate whether my Y hat is correct?
germayne: is there a way for me to measure the whiteheads correctly? I can, right? Because I have the loss.
germayne: I put in the Y and the Y hat.
germayne: And this basically tells me whether it's good or bad.
germayne: Good. Obe.
germayne: Agreed?
germayne: You guys able to follow so far? So, you notice that when I do a forward pass, when I just force the thing to do the matrix multiplication, I basically get an output.
germayne: So, at this stage, right, I can actually measure whether the output is good or not. Agree?
germayne: I can measure it.
germayne: So once I measure it, I should be able to go back and tell the weights that, okay, I think there are some areas that you're not doing well, can you please adjust?
germayne: Because now I have a way to measure, right? I know how to measure whether it's good or bad. Maybe for the first time, your model predicts the house pricing is all wrong. Predicts everything to be nonsense value.
germayne: Right? So using the loss function is able to now guide it somehow, right, in order to update W.
germayne: Right, so I'll update W, update W, update W. So you notice, right, the direction here is…
germayne: in order to propagate the information back, because the L, the loss is only computed here.
germayne: To go back and update all of them, I have to go in this direction.
germayne: I update this guy.
germayne: The one at the end gets updated first, followed by this guy, followed by this guy, followed by this guy. Oh, it's actually the input don't have, sorry.
germayne: So we only update 3 times. W3, W2, and then W1 will be the last person to get updated.
germayne: Okay, now, can I ask you guys the intuition? Is… is one time, is it enough?
germayne: you know, if I just go there, is it done? No, right? So I need to do this multiple times. So what you do again, right, is the intuition standpoint is you start to do the second look.
germayne: So from here, you do, you do, you go again.
germayne: Because the by-right, the W has adjusted already, so you go through one stage, one arrow, you calculate this again.
germayne: You get the information of the new Y. Okay, shit, let's go back and update the guys again.
germayne: So now you guys understand why people call forward pass and backward pass, right? You go forward, then you go backward, you go forward, then you go backward, you go forward, then you go backward.
germayne: This is essentially where the model is training.
germayne: So far, makes sense?
germayne: or confused.
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: But how do you know, how much to… At the weights.
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Right, what possibly?
germayne: Haven't go there yet. Haven't talked about that yet.
germayne: Fantastic question, haven't thought about that yet. That one, I will come next.
germayne: So, we still got a… we still got a missing piece, right? How to update.
germayne: So, so, I'm giving it in a very hand-wavy manner. Somehow, mathematically, I can tell, like, HW, like, oh man, dude, you are the lousiest, please update yourself, right? Maybe W2 doing well, okay, W2, you've done pretty good. Maybe don't change too much. Hey, W1, mmm… okay.
germayne: So the idea here is, we still haven't talked about how to update them, right? But the flow here is that forward propagation
germayne: It basically means predicting, you're just going forward. Backward propagation means that you're just going backwards. Somehow you need to pass some kind of information from your output backwards in order to update W.
germayne: I have not talked about how to update yet, that's where the math will come in.
germayne: Haven't talked about that yet.
germayne: But… At this point in time, anybody…
germayne: Lost, and need me to repeat again.
Edwin Yap: Can you repeat again?
germayne: API again.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Whoa.
germayne: Who is that? Who is that? I cannot see. The screen not big enough.
germayne: Oh, one last minute.
Edwin Yap: trust is…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, I mean…
Edwin Yap: Every now, every day.
germayne: Okay, so I'll repeat again, huh? Repeat this part again.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: I try to…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: is it okay to think, like, you know, like, the backward propagation isn't making the input the out, the, making the output the input?
germayne: No, no, no, no.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Cool.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: you got your X, which is your input data. It's basically like your Kaggle data.
germayne: Your goal here is you want to find W, you want to find… okay, again, I put the… I pinned the goal at the top. This is the goal, I'm not going to delete this.
germayne: Your goal, right, is I want to train a model, and when I say train a model, it means I want to find a W, because W defines the model's identity.
germayne: I want to find a W so that…
germayne: If I take in W and take in the X, I will predict a good prediction between the actual target label versus what I predicted.
germayne: Correct?
germayne: So can I ask, right, in this case, what is changing? Can my X change or not?
germayne: In this context, can the X change?
germayne: Can I change my X? Or is X fixed?
Zac Ang: Like, 6.
germayne: X is fixed, right? Because X is your data.
germayne: Correct? You decided what data to use, X is fixed. Let's say Noel decided that, okay, I got 50 features. Train model, X is fixed, right? 50, 50 by N.
germayne: So what is changing here is your W, because in this equation, only W can change, mah. If W becomes better, then W multiplied by X gives me a better prediction, so W is changing. Now, I haven't talked about how to change W yet. So what the neural network does is, you want to do what is called a forward.
germayne: This direction, huh? Left to right. So basically, it's basically the math that I did. You take X,
germayne: You multiply by W, And then you take the next layer.
germayne: You multiply by W2. And then you take the next layer, You multiply by W3.
germayne: Basically, I get my output right, right?
germayne: First, first time, right? Let's say the first, the first, the first, the first batch.
germayne: I get a white hat. But then my question to you guys is, is white hat good or not? Here, if I do it one time…
germayne: Then, like, hey, you guys will be like, the W also haven't found yet what? But I need to start somewhere, so the W, I can put some random value, right? I put some… I put everything to be 0 law, 0, 0, 0.
germayne: then my prediction will just be zero, ma. Right? Then, the first house is $500K, becomes zero. Aw, shit! Your error is…
germayne: Wow, very big, okay, your arrow is very big, your mean square arrow is very big, right?
germayne: So…
germayne: Once you calculate the first Y hat, you basically can measure how good you have done, correct? Because you have your Y, and how do you measure that? You use your loss function, your mean square arrow.
germayne: Or, if it's a classification, you use your cross entropy.
germayne: So, you have a way to measure whether good or bad, and then now, what you want to do is, with this information, you can go back and update your W3, W2, and W1.
germayne: Which is why it's called backwards. So, you take your information you collected already.
germayne: You know who is doing well or who is doing bad, you go and update them.
germayne: In this direction, backwards. So backwards is because, from the output layer, it just flows backwards. So, W3 gets updated first, W2 gets updated, then by W1.
germayne: Once I have the new Ws, can I make a prediction again? Of course you can, because I want to test out whether if W has improved.
germayne: So you do, you do the same again, you do this.
germayne: How to do this?
germayne: You go forward again.
germayne: Takeaway here is, you notice that there's going to be many rounds. Go forward, go backward, go forward, go backward. Multiple times.
germayne: I have not talked about how many times.
germayne: But the idea here is when people say, like, wah.
germayne: Meta has 100 overk of GPU. The LLM takes, like, 30 days to train.
germayne: That means that the whole process takes, like, very, very long.
germayne: Got it?
germayne: I mean… Ken? Cannot?
Edwin Yap: And thanks…
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So, like what Philip is asking, okay, I talk about this very hand-wavy thing. How do I know how to update? Yeah, that's where the math comes in.
germayne: Yeah, you see, I've got one section here.
germayne: You see? I prepared one section here, right?
germayne: So, one gap here that we never talk about is that I talk about it in a very hand-wavy way. Oh, when the thing come back, how does it update? We are going to make use of gradient descent.
germayne: What does gradient descent teach us? I'm going to write here. Gradient descent says that if I can iterate X, again, if it's F of X,
germayne: If I always update X, Followed by the gradient.
germayne: this direction, If I do this, Basically, I can find… X?
germayne: Such a dip.
germayne: F of X is…
germayne: minimize. You can see, right? This is the thing that I wrote just now, gradient descent.
germayne: So, if you, if you, if you write it again from a, from a, from a, from a backpropagation standpoint, same thing. I got W,
germayne: I got W.
germayne: Right? So W also got a T, because there's going to be many W's.
germayne: I can update W, right?
germayne: if I follow the laws, DL over DW. So basically, DL over DW basically says that I can find W,
germayne: such that L is… Minimize.
germayne: Can you see the distinction in radiant descent? It's the same thing, right? I'm doing the same. So basically, this, this, this key, this thing is key in how we are going to adjust the W. Notice this equation. So, we are going to adjust W bit by bit.
germayne: So by right, right, W, W, the first W is always going to be nonsense. But after W, iterate multiple times using this equation.
germayne: W will get better.
germayne: W gets better.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: And this is actually done using a lot of math. I can show some basic example.
germayne: or enough.
germayne: Enough? Enough math?
Gwendalynn Lim: No, sure.
germayne: Sure.
germayne: Okay, I do, I do a very, very simple, I do a very, very simple one, okay? But I think this is a takeaway. So if, let's say, you don't want the math right, just remember this.
germayne: So you already have the answer of how to update W. So this tells you how is W updated. W is adjusted slowly.
germayne: W is adjusted slowly by moving towards the negative direction of the gradient. This I can always calculate.
germayne: is DL over DW, I can calculate this.
germayne: Right? So what this means is that the W, right, usually you initialize random numbers.
germayne: Let's just say zero lah.
germayne: Eventually, right, every step, the W keeps changing.
germayne: I'm just writing trash values here lah, you guys get the idea, right? So, every iteration, the W keeps changing, right? Becomes better and better and better and better, right? You can see, this equation just basically means that the W keeps changing.
germayne: No.
germayne: Of course, the gap here, right, where the math happens is actually how do you calculate DL over DW?
germayne: That's actually where the math would start.
germayne: Right, so now, now, up till this point, you guys already get the answer of how W… how W
germayne: gets updated. The gap here is… how to get… DL over DW.
germayne: How do you actually get DR over DW? So the idea here is that DR over DW
germayne: You notice, you notice just now I mentioned this thing called backpropagation, which means that somehow you need to… you need to update them iteratively from the back to the front.
germayne: You notice I mentioned this, right? It's called backpropagation. I start with the output, I updated W3, W2, and W1. You notice that there's a reason I'm saying this, it's because you cannot update W1 without updating W3 first. It's backwards.
germayne: So the hint here is that to get this DL over DW, right, this gradient, it needs to start from the back, it needs to start from the tail, because this is where the loss is calculated.
germayne: So, the gradient is calculated, and the gradient is propagated backwards.
germayne: So the flow goes backwards.
germayne: Right, the data flow goes like that.
germayne: And…
germayne: the math here, right, if you, if you again take Andrew Erng's one, right, you just see that it's basically just this thing called Chenu.
germayne: Chen Ru just basically says that if it's DF over DX, right.
germayne: what I can… what I can do is I take D, DF over DY, multiply by DY over DX.
germayne: So you notice, right, I can calculate
germayne: DF over DX, even if I do not have access to calculate it. I just need to take this guy, multiply by this guy.
germayne: So, again, the idea here is that why do we need to flow the gradient backwards? It's because we call it the downstream gradient. The downstream gradient will give us the hint to calculate DL over DW.
germayne: Okay? And it needs to flow backwards.
germayne: So, takeaway here is, now you understand why gradient flow is very important. So, I think I mentioned, if you go all the way back, alright.
germayne: You know what I like about what I'm saying sometimes is that if you were to watch this on repeat.
germayne: So let's say if you were to watch my… what I… if you guys are recording and you watch it again, right?
germayne: If you were to watch it twice, right, I think whatever that I say in the front will make sense when you're now at the back.
germayne: So just now, I think half an hour ago, I talked about the gradient. I said, like, oh man, the gradient here is zero. So then the idea here is that, okay, why is a gradient flow important? It's because if the gradient cannot flow well, then the intuition is that when I'm flowing backwards, right, maybe some guys at the back doesn't get the full benefit.
germayne: Correct? It's just like… it's just like, maybe today, somebody baked bread for me. If I don't pass the bread down to Philip, right, I eat… I eat everything left, nothing, then I give Philip, hey, Philip.
germayne: I got no bread left.
germayne: Then there's nothing for you to fill your hunger, right? So people at the back doesn't benefit.
germayne: So the intuition here is that the gradient flow is very dependent on what you put in front in all the layers, so that the gradient needs to flow backwards.
germayne: And… We need to use chain rule.
germayne: And one very, very basic example is you have your W here, right, if you remember. This is just one block.
germayne: You have your in, you have your out.
germayne: You're out. Just now I call it Z. You're in, I call it X. Just now.
germayne: So actually, at every step, right, it needs to do a… it needs to do a… it needs to do a very simple backpropagation, where I'm going to use chain rule to calculate
germayne: this. So, my goal here is to find DL over DW, right? How to find DL over DW. So, I can use chain rule to find DL over DW, and it's basically something like this. I take the differential with respect to DL, I take DL, I guess call it DL, right? I multiply by something called DL,
germayne: over D in.
germayne: Okay, so basically the idea here is I can just multiply these.
germayne: this one, this one, right, D out over D in, right?
germayne: If, let's say your formula is like that, so let's say Z equals to W dot X, if I were to differentiate Z with respect to X, it's actually basically W. You notice a? I'm saying D out over D in, right? So basically DZ over DX.
germayne: W dot X, if I were to differentiate.
germayne: Z with respect to W, sorry, Z with respect to X, I basically get W. So actually, this one is just your W. Your this one, right, is actually passed from…
germayne: Pass… from the N. So basically, this thing, right, is always passed down from people in front.
germayne: So people in front is passing down, I calculate, I pass down, I calculate, I pass down. And this term is always changing, by the way. So let's say if I pass half a bread to Philip, Philip eats half.
germayne: And then Philip choose to add some ingredients on it. The thing will be different, and then he choose to pass down.
germayne: Correct.
germayne: So you can see the intuition here lah, alright, is that…
germayne: We are, you know, we are kind of using gradient descent to update W, and we are passing the upstream gradient downwards to the back. So what's the takeaway?
germayne: Takeaway number one is, you learned that gradient descent is used to update W.
germayne: Okay? Number two, takeaway is that the gradient passing down is very important.
germayne: If you… if you build very inefficient architecture?
germayne: the gradient cannot flow down, what do you think will happen? Why not make a guess? Can I ask you guys a question? Let's say if W3 benefited, but W1 don't get any gradient, what do you think will happen to W?
germayne: If you look at the equation here, look at this.
germayne: If the gradient doesn't get passed down, what happens to W?
germayne: What happens with W1?
Zac Ang: Is it time zero? Because it's my.
germayne: Exactly, exactly, basically, nothing right, nothing gets passed down. W don't get updated.
germayne: And can I ask you guys.
germayne: would it work if W3 is very good, but W1 and W2 is shit?
germayne: It won't work, right? It's just like a basketball team. You've got LeBron James, but everybody is like me.
germayne: then it won't work, right? Only one shooter, then the rest cannot even pass.
germayne: So the idea here, again, right, is that the takeaway is that if the gradient cannot flow backwards, the other weights cannot get updated, and it's a bad thing.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, I'll leave this here, but if you… again, right, I just want to repeat. If you don't know the math, it's okay. Take away is, we are using gradient descent, this equation here.
germayne: Is to showcase that gradient descent is used To update the width.
germayne: And then, let's say, again, if you think about people asking in an interview, why is the loss function differentiable matter? If the loss function is not differentiable, how am I going to find… how am I going to do all of this? I can't even pass the gradient down, right? I can't even pass anything.
germayne: Can't even update W. I can't even find DL over DW.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So actually, you see, it's not that bad, right?
germayne: So, if you record it, Watch this multiple times.
germayne: Okay, and one last thing, right, one last thing, right, I think I never mentioned… if you notice, right, I'm a bit sneaky. You notice that actually I add in… I add in a term here.
germayne: I add in one term here. So basically, this term, right, is usually what people call the learning rate.
germayne: I'm not sure if you guys remember, I mentioned this.
germayne: So basically, the learning rate, right, you basically, if you set it to be very small, let's say if you set it to be 0.01, what happens?
germayne: Basically, I need to take a lot more steps to update the equation, correct?
germayne: So if I set learning rate to be very small, basically I need a lot more steps to update.
germayne: And actually, it's not by chance that I intentionally leave this out.
germayne: So if you, if you look at this, where
germayne: I'm going to showcase the same gradient descent thing again.
germayne: So, you see, if you look at my screen.
germayne: You see that if I… the equation is like that.
germayne: There's an alpha multiplied by the differential… the gradient.
germayne: If you set the learning rate to be very big, right, obviously, each step is going to be very big. So what will happen is, I'm going to create one random one here, you see, huh?
germayne: You see, the jump is very big, right? Each jump is very big.
germayne: if I set the learning rate to be very, very tiny, 0.01 is actually quite a common one lah, right?
germayne: You can see that it takes more steps.
germayne: Correct?
germayne: So then the intuition here is that, hey man, why do we want to take some small steps?
germayne: The reality here is that, I think just now, like what Grant asked, your function is not going to be so smooth, man. And the idea is that if you are taking very huge steps, you might overstep, because maybe there's a… there's a… there's a… there's a… there's a hole here.
germayne: Right, maybe, maybe your equation, I don't know how it looks like, lah, maybe there's a hole here, and then it's like that.
germayne: Maybe you, from here, if you take very big step, you jump to here already. You might have missed out your step. So therefore, people usually say that, okay, maybe the trade-off is we take tiny steps. But what do you think is the trade-off of taking tiny steps? You basically need to wait a long, longer time, right?
germayne: The backpropagation is going to need to do it much more, much more times.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so actually, we… congrats! We actually got past the hurdles. This is actually, that's it. This is the hard part.
germayne: Everything else is okay already.
germayne: Okay, so actually, this is, what I've gone through lah. You can just take your time to read.
germayne: Okay, so now, actually, in practice, what does it, what does it, what does it, what does it mean? I think, in practice.
germayne: Basically, the decision here is, like, it's going to be complex, because…
germayne: You need to decide how many hidden layers, and then within the hidden layers, you need to decide how many nodes.
germayne: Of course, the bigger the node, the more complex, the more overfitting it might possibly be.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So we'll talk a bit about other techniques to do regularization.
germayne: Our good friend L1 and L2NOM will come back again, if you guys remember.
germayne: Talk about the math in linear regression, it's the same guy again.
germayne: Exact same thing, we're gonna talk about it, right? So actually, you can add some regularization, and we'll talk about regularization, I believe, on Thursday.
germayne: Okay, again, here are just some, good general guidelines. Start small. Again, the idea here is you start small because you don't want to immediately overfit. You want to start by underfitting the model, and then you start overfit, start to overfit.
germayne: But in practice, in practice, my best recommendation is
germayne: If you are… you are… if, let's say you're trying to solve a problem.
germayne: And the immediate first thought is to build a neural network.
germayne: yourself, Just remember that it's a huge red flag.
germayne: That there's actually an easier option, you're just choosing the hardest way out.
germayne: Okay? Just remember that. Remember this takeaway.
germayne: Okay? That if, let's say, you want to solve a problem, the immediate first thing you want to come to your head is, I want to use a neural network, and you want to build it yourself.
germayne: Right, which means you define how does a neural network looks like. You're obviously taking the harder route. There's going to be an easier solution.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so, obviously, whatever that we learned for the parameters of the neural network still works, right? Whatever that you have thought still works.
germayne: But you cannot do hyperparameter tuning for the architecture.
germayne: Architecture basically means What are the label blocks that you want to put?
germayne: Right? You obviously cannot hyperparameter tune it. I'm sure some of you guys already felt that, right? You guys asked me, wow.
germayne: You know, when I do the Kaggle, it takes, like, 3 hours.
germayne: train 20 model takes 3 hours. If you use neural network, right, I think you can wait until, like, the whole… your whole afternoon, you just basically wait for it.
germayne: Okay? So, it's not, not scalable.
germayne: Alright.
germayne: Okay. Actually, we really got through the hard part already. We got through the hard part already. Really. That's the hard part.
germayne: So… Obviously, obviously, I'm omitting some details.
germayne: But the Gs… It's… the G's for the math part is covered.
germayne: Okay? You should now understand about backpropagation. I omitted a few key details, some nuance. If you start to work it out, you'll be like, oh my shit, how come, like, I never mentioned? Intentional. Okay? Now, I think we are going to go towards the application side.
germayne: Talk a bit about industry practice, okay? Obviously, obviously, your question to me is that, hey man, does it need to know about backpropagation? Need to know or not?
germayne: My advice is that I feel that knowing a lot of this, I think, helps a lot.
germayne: Right? If let's say you… let's say for any one of you, if your intention is to go very deep in future, right, like, you really want to go very deep into neural networks, I feel like the foundation is important.
germayne: Okay? But if, let's say, you're just doing it for fun, I don't think the math matters, because you can just do the code.
germayne: the library will just do the differential for you, and I'll show you guys how the library does it later.
germayne: Okay? Do you guys think, like, there's someone calculating the thing for you? Will you guys think that?
germayne: The A must do differential, right?
germayne: Do you guys think, like, anybody's calculating that for you? Is there a monkey behind your computer, like, calculating?
germayne: Like, oh, okay, I calculate this, it's not right. So I'll show you guys how the library does it.
germayne: So, I think in practice, for the industry, there's actually very two big libraries. There's PyTorch, and there's TensorFlow, for those of you that know.
germayne: I started using them 10 years ago, right? 10 years ago, TensorFlow was the one that's dominating, but nowadays, it has moved to PyTorch.
germayne: Why is it that I like PyTorch? It's because
germayne: if you understand the theory that I went through, every single thing that I just did.
germayne: And if you were to write the PyTorch code, you will see that it's actually very similar. You'll do forward.
germayne: You'll do backward.
germayne: And then you'll do… you'll update.
germayne: Very similar. Basically, the function, you can define this. So, from a theory standpoint, well, I love it because it holds, right?
germayne: And I think PyTorch has gained a lot of popularity, because it's very easy to write the code.
germayne: Compared to TensorFlow back then.
germayne: Right? But now, nowadays, TensorFlow, 10 years ago, TensorFlow used to have a wrapper called Keras.
germayne: But now they have merged.
germayne: Since Keras 2.0. So what does that mean?
germayne: It means that, actually, if you use Keras and if you use PyTorch, right, the library is actually very similar.
germayne: So then the question to you guys is, do you think it matters if you learn PyTorch or learn TensorFlow? Do you think it matters? It doesn't really matter, to… okay, it matters to some extent, because back then, right.
germayne: being able to write very good, architecture, it's a scale. Not everybody can write it. Let's say if there's a paper, not everybody knows how to write it automatically. But I think now we've…
germayne: your large language model, I don't think it's that important.
germayne: Right? Moreover, but the point I'm just pointing out here is that actually both PyTorch and TensorFlow are very similar now. Although my preference is still PyTorch, I have a very deep bias to prefer PyTorch.
germayne: But… Why? And the question here is that, okay, why should I use TensorFlow then?
germayne: Because, you know who's the creator of TensorFlow? The creator of TensorFlow is Google. So if there's a new…
germayne: model that's published by Google.
germayne: Where do you think it gets implemented first?
germayne: it gets implemented in TensorFlow.
germayne: Right?
germayne: So, what's the takeaway?
germayne: Takeaway is that if you know everything, fantastic, doesn't matter. Cannot be that. Imagine you don't know, TensorFlow, then it's like, oh, the paper come out, like, oh shit, I have to wait for PyTorch to implement. That doesn't make sense, right? So… so here's from Google, this one is from Meta.
germayne: But it has gotten very, very popular nowadays. Another reason why TensorFlow is very good is, if you guys understand, there's this thing called TPU that Google created.
germayne: Anybody knows what TPU is?
Zac Ang: Insert Processing Unit.
germayne: Yep, but what is it?
germayne: What's the big deal?
germayne: What's the big deal with a TPU?
germayne: So a TPU is a hardware created by Google, has a replacement of GPU.
germayne: And it's actually highly optimized with TensorFlow.
germayne: Okay? So there are some benefits to TensorFlow. Of course, I think PyTorch with TPU is possible, but it's not officially written by Google.
germayne: So I think people has to do the connectivity with TPU.
germayne: So…
germayne: If you really ask my preference, I like PyTorch, but it doesn't matter, because I remember I also implemented in TensorFlow because, there were some libraries that I wanted from TensorFlow, so I also wrote stuff in TensorFlow.
germayne: Okay, I'm going to leave these things for you guys to read. PyTorch is used by a lot of people, lah. Everyone use PyTorch lah, basically.
germayne: TensorFlow as well, from Google. So these two libraries. Okay, I want to talk about this auto-grab, right? So this is just a bonus.
germayne: Right.
germayne: That probably you might not… See people talk about this.
germayne: Okay, so you get a bonus… you get a bonus lesson.
germayne: Okay, so what I want to show you guys, right, is that…
germayne: You know, when we learn about the whole module today, right, the takeaway, right?
germayne: will be there.
germayne: You learn about gradient descent.
germayne: And from gradient descent, you learn that you need to find the deverity, which is the differential, the first order differential.
germayne: So what this means is that you need to learn how to differentiate something, right, the loss function.
germayne: So what this means, again, right, is actually the intuition will be that actually, you know, when we do the exercise, we're always doing by hand.
germayne: But actually, how does the… how does the PyTorch actually do the differentiation? Actually, they have something called the automatic differentiation.
germayne: Which means that as long as the function is differentiable and is broken down in each of the aromatic transformations.
germayne: the TensorFlow, or the PyTorch library, they automatically will be able to do the differentiation for you. And how it works here is I use a very simple example. Look at this function. X1,
germayne: Multiply by X2 plus sine x squared multiplied by X1. Sorry, right? This is the function.
germayne: X1 multiplied by X2 plus sine of X squared.
germayne: Suppose you put an input of X1 equals to 2 and X2 equals to 1.
germayne: Right? You want to do the gradient flow. How do you actually do it?
germayne: The idea here is that the automatic differentiation actually breaks them down into a tree, into a graph.
germayne: Right? So you can see right here, X1 and X2 times multiplied together, right? X1 multiplied by X2, plus… so these two plus sign, you can see plus sign.
germayne: And then you get F. So this one is sine of X, right, sine of X squared. So basically, we broke down this equation into a graph, and using this graph, we can actually, you know, automatically, the library will handle the gradient flow, because the gradient flow backwards. So you see, it's the same thing again.
germayne: Right? Which is why you need to know about the back propagation.
germayne: I'm able to do a calculation, DF over DF,
germayne: I can basically calculate, you know, the gradient flow all the way back.
germayne: And actually, the automatic differentiation is actually very smart. It knows how to distribute the gradient automatically for you, right? So you can see.
germayne: First step.
germayne: X1 and X2.
germayne: I calculate the input, right? So this one, I put… I sub in the input of X equals to 2, X equals to 1.
germayne: Calculate, I go under the front. And from here, I need to do backward.
germayne: Right? Backward.
germayne: From here, I know that the derivative is 1. So, if it's a plus, you basically just flow the gradient. 1 is just flow downwards.
germayne: Right? And then after that here, you've got multiply.
germayne: And then here, because it's multiplication, you take the gradient flow 1, you multiply by X1, so that's why it's 1. 1 multiplied by 2, here you get 2.
germayne: Here, again, you flow the gradient back here, and then you flow back to 1.
germayne: Right, you can see here, we just do F of X, we just… sine becomes cosine, right, if you differentiate.
germayne: So basically, we can really apply the calculation, and you can see that everything just flows back.
germayne: So the takeaway here is that you don't have to write that analytical form. This is the one that human calculated. But PyTorch is able to handle the
germayne: Flow for you.
germayne: That's just a takeaway.
germayne: So, what's the takeaway from here? Takeaway from here is gradient flow is very important.
germayne: How the model is learning, Really highly depends if the gradient can flow backwards.
germayne: Okay? And the gradient is just a mechanism for us to… Update the width.
germayne: That is a takeaway. Okay, the math is not important, just to show you that when you write PyTorch, it will just do the automatic differentiation for you.
germayne: Okay, anybody excited for this, or like,
Gwendalynn Lim: Is this your own program that you made, this, this page, Automatic Differentiation?
germayne: All this, I use Clockwork to do it for me.
germayne: I mean, the concept, I want to illustrate this, but I want to…
germayne: do this for you, but yeah, this is written by LLM.
germayne: The interactivity is not written by me, but I want to convey this concept.
germayne: Why, it's very nice, is it?
Gwendalynn Lim: Yeah, pretty good.
germayne: Yeah.
Zac Ang: question… How do you know what's the correct loss function to use?
Zac Ang: Through the different person on.
germayne: Very good question, very good question. Fantastic question. Okay, so the… there's two, there's two… there's two… two… there's two answers to this, okay? Superficial and easy answer is there's going to be general rule of thumb.
germayne: Your regression problem is always going to be either mean square error, root mean square error, MAE.
germayne: These are only that few.
germayne: functions that you can differentiate. You can't create a lot of differential functions that can be differentiated. You can create custom ones, but most of the time, 90% of the time.
germayne: Whatever was taught would work.
germayne: Same for… Classification is going to be cross entropy.
germayne: That's the easy answer. Now, the hard answer.
germayne: Again, it depends on how you want to formulate your problem. If you want to formulate it, just now, I think that time I mentioned, right, you can actually convert your regression problem to classification, then your loss will naturally be quasentropy.
germayne: Right? There are many losses if you were to explore very deeper. If you explore deeper, there are many, many losses. Of course, that's not taught today. That tries to counter certain stuff, but in general, the losses are finite.
germayne: It's not like, well, suddenly, after this course, there's 200 over losses. It's not.
germayne: The losses are, at most, maybe 10, there's 10 of it, 10 different versions.
germayne: Right, so that's the good news. Does that, does that answer?
germayne: So in practice, if you do it enough, you will see that it doesn't deviate too much.
germayne: Okay?
Zac Ang: Oh, in a way, the neural network is, like, a very long and complicated linear regression that is, like, boosted linear regression.
germayne: No, it's not linear regression, because if you add in the linear layers, it is stronger than linear regression.
germayne: It's not a linear regression.
germayne: Okay, I think… I think my math, I omitted… I omitted one part, just to tell you guys, I omitted the… I omitted the… the… the activation.
germayne: So if you guys want to be, like, like, 100% accurate, let me just show one last… one last update.
germayne: Okay, so that you guys don't get confused.
germayne: Okay? So, if you go back to the block, we are going back to that same block that I introduced at the start.
germayne: You have X, You have W1.
germayne: You have W2,
germayne: And then you have X. This one, I have shown that if you don't put linear layers, it's just essentially W1, W2, X.
germayne: Actually, to be more accurate, is… W1X.
germayne: NW2. This is linear regression, correct?
germayne: But I introduce non-linear layers, so what happens is.
germayne: you have W1, here you have a nonlinear layer, This is your activation one.
germayne: And then you have your W2.
germayne: And then here, usually, let's say, if it's classification, it's your sigmoid.
germayne: Then here is X. Sorry, then here is Y. Had. So basically, your formula now becomes like that. V1, X,
germayne: Activation 1.
germayne: Right?
germayne: Multiply by 2.
germayne: And then I have sigmat.
germayne: This is not linear.
germayne: Understand?
germayne: Okay, just to be clear, I omitted this, obviously, to make the thing simpler.
germayne: But you notice that you can stack the nonlinearity, the whole thing will be nonlinear, it will no longer be linear. So the function you learn is no longer just a straight line, it's not just a straight line. It's very powerful, very expressive.
germayne: That's why I can overfit. If you are not careful, you can overfit like crazy.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Got it?
germayne: Okay, so I think with this, right.
germayne: If you can gain this foundation.
germayne: the rest of the module becomes easier, because we are all building upon the same concept. We are no longer introducing anything new.
Gwendalynn Lim: I would like to learn about growth, please.
germayne: Sorry?
Gwendalynn Lim: Oh, sorry, querying Gemini at the same time you're talking.
germayne: Yeah, okay.
germayne: Okay? So, we will introduce something… I would say… I would say for computer vision, to be honest, I think it's even easier, because we no longer need to repeat about the whole thing again, we no longer need to talk about backpropagation anyways.
germayne: So now it's just new LEGO blocks, okay? But the foundation here is you learn how internally the neural network gets the update.
germayne: And I will share this slide.
germayne: With you guys in the annotation folder.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: I hope… I hope that people that enjoys the math enjoys the math, people that don't like the math also gets the takeaway.
germayne: Okay, it's optional.
germayne: Okay, so fantastic, I think we are really right on time, so I think…
germayne: Anybody needs any break more? Any more break, or we just finished?
germayne: We can continue on.
germayne: Okay, so what will happen is soon we'll just go through the… Okay, so if you notice in your notebook, one thing to prefix is that the notebook doesn't follow the same sequence as the lesson today, and I think it's okay.
germayne: Right? What you learned today, on the whole, is this whole story of
germayne: how do you actually understand neural network? So the notebook, the sequence will be different.
germayne: It might not start with gradient descent first, but it's okay, because you guys already understand that.
germayne: So, we won't be going through all the materials in the notebook. The notebook will just further enrich what I have taught. Same content.
germayne: What will happen is that soon we'll go through with you how does the neural network looks like from an end-to-end perspective, from a Titanic standpoint.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, I'll hand over to Sun to do the notebook, yeah.
Soon | NTU: Hey, thanks, Mick. How about the… meet MNIS dataset.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, you can… you… I mean, you go through… you can go through with… with any of… I think you can go through with the MNIS, because, convolutional neural network, I believe, will probably use it, right? So…
Soon | NTU: Okay.
germayne: You can start with the MDs lah, yeah.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so…
germayne: So, MNIS, by the way, is like the iris for computer vision.
germayne: Just so you guys know what we are talking about. So, the iris is the flower, right? So, the Mnis is the handwritten digit that Yin Le Kun famously used.
germayne: So if you guys don't know who Yen Lokong is, you can just go and Google him.
germayne: He's the creator for convolutional neural network.
germayne: But yeah. Yeah. Go ahead.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so… In the outline, right.
Soon | NTU: Module 3.7, Jupyter Notebook. Okay, so please go to this, section on the building MLP.
Soon | NTU: multi-layer perceptron, with the PyTorch section.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so that will bring you to this, section here.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: So now, the first part of the notebook, right? So basically, we just show you
Soon | NTU: the… a very simple version of the MLP, multi-layer perceptron, okay? And that, okay, just briefly, one example, to…
Soon | NTU: illustrate, okay, with a simple MLP, okay.
Soon | NTU: with some linear, so-called the activation function, okay, you will not be able to use it to solve some of the problem. There is some, limitation and constraint, alright? So that is why, in the later part of this search repeated notebook.
Soon | NTU: we… and, Jermaine has also introduced this activation function. Again, this is what brings the non-linearity into the deep learning, right? And… and make, the deep learning architecture so powerful.
Soon | NTU: And it's able to solve a very complex, problem, okay? So, I won't go to that. You can read through the content.
Soon | NTU: And I will quickly go through…
Soon | NTU: go to this section here, okay? So, now the focus now is To see how,
Soon | NTU: neural network, okay, or we call it multi-layer perceptron, not single-layer, multi-layer can be implemented using this PyTorch, right?
Soon | NTU: Let me… I think this…
Soon | NTU: Okay, so… PyTorch, we need to import all the necessary library.
Soon | NTU: Right, so I think this is, very simple, and the dataset which we're going to use for illustration of the, setting up this PyTorch, neural network is, MNIST, dataset, so it basically contains, some images of, handwritten digits
Soon | NTU: Right? Not something, syntactic, but I think they have, captured the handwritten digit from…
Soon | NTU: Digit 0 to 9, okay, single digit per image, okay, with a resolution of 28 by 28 pixel grayscale.
Soon | NTU: Right? So I think this, dataset gave us a very good, warm-up for the test day, which will be covering, computer vision, right? Now,
Soon | NTU: PyTorch way of, Has given us some tool
Soon | NTU: Okay, and also some utilities, so-called the, functions to allow us to, so-called.
Soon | NTU: make our training and also the, pre-processing of our data set, be it training or at the, inference stage, okay, much easier. Okay, so it is slightly different from the TensorFlow way of, you know, managing this,
Soon | NTU: training data and test data, okay, so… Nope.
Soon | NTU: They use this thing called the, you know, the data set, this class, okay, is able to let you download the data, you know, from the internet into your
Soon | NTU: local, drive.
Soon | NTU: Right? You can find it in your…
Soon | NTU: current directory.pyTorch job, you will see something there. Okay, so if your disk space is running out of
Soon | NTU: space, so do remember to do some house skipping in this folder, because some of the file… I think the NLP, I'm not sure whether you'll be downloading file also, in a similar way, because we will be using PyTorch as well.
Soon | NTU: to do the NLP next week, right? Now.
Soon | NTU: Of course, for visualization, we still can leverage on our… the Mapoplib.
Soon | NTU: Okay, all the spotting library to do in visualizes is a digit 5. It's not very, sharp, because it's only 28 by 28, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay? So there's some kind of,
Soon | NTU: just give you some idea lah, because I've done some research, okay? So, trying to understand what this code is trying to do, okay? So, I think…
Soon | NTU: some of the challenges of using PyTorch, okay, so maybe not for Jermaine, but, is…
Soon | NTU: We… we need to… to… deal with a lot of tensors. Okay, so tensor is equivalent to our NumPy.
Soon | NTU: be known.
Soon | NTU: sklearn. Okay, so Tensor, you know, you can actually run this in your GPU.
Soon | NTU: Right? Okay, for…
Soon | NTU: for better performance, okay? Because NumPy, you… you can't… you can't run it on a GPU, okay? Parallel processing. So, now this one is basically to…
Soon | NTU: try to do some, unnormalization, undo the normalization, because, I think at the very beginning, we have this image, right? Right? We need to visualize it, we have to display in this
Soon | NTU: From 0 to 2 Wi-Fi.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we need to do some, we call it…
Soon | NTU: undo normalization, okay, to be able to visualize your image like this, okay? And then, the next step is…
Soon | NTU: our image input data, right?
Soon | NTU: is Grayscale.
Soon | NTU: 28x28, okay, so, pyTorch will store our tensor in this manner.
Soon | NTU: 3 digits.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: The first one is a channel, so with grayscale, it's only one channel, and then the height and the width.
Soon | NTU: Right? So, this is something, make the whole thing very challenging, because if you want to do training, yeah, you have to do a lot of reshaping, right, which you will see over here. Okay, now, over here we have this class, usually, if you're trying to make your code more, reusable.
Soon | NTU: Right? We would not try to do these, you know, terms at the very beginning until the end, okay? Usually, we package our logic of our code into a class definition like this.
Soon | NTU: Okay? And then this is the init, which is the,
Soon | NTU: We call it the constructor for this class, so when you create something, this…
Soon | NTU: Fuel line will be run once.
Soon | NTU: per object that you create, okay? And then this is the logic for your forward pass.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so there is some kind of,
Soon | NTU: required to reshape your input, okay, because your image come in as an input. It's not like your data frame, okay?
Soon | NTU: you do not need to flatten it, but if your input is an image, 28 by 28, okay, so you need to put everything into one dimension, okay? So I have a…
Soon | NTU: 1… Okay, so this view basically is to flatten the image, okay, because you've
Soon | NTU: before you feed it into the next layer, which is a hidden layer, okay? So the first layer in our network, PyTalk network, is the input layer, right? Like this.
Soon | NTU: So… We cannot use this raw.
Soon | NTU: for the next layer, okay, we need to flatten it, right? So, it doesn't come from data frame, it is already in this format. Okay, so it's only when we are dealing with image, then we need to convert this 2x2
Soon | NTU: Into a one-dimensional so-called a number like this.
Soon | NTU: Okay? No.
Soon | NTU: What makes it more complicated is, we have this, batch size that we have specified when we import this,
Soon | NTU: When we set up the training data, Right, bed size, 64 means.
Soon | NTU: At every iteration, you are going to pass a chunk of 64 images
Soon | NTU: at a time. Not one by one, okay, because it's going to be very slow. Six evil images at a time, and go through one training.
Soon | NTU: And then you get some kind of,
Soon | NTU: The weights adjusted, and then you go to the next batch of 64, okay, and so on, until you
Soon | NTU: Consume the whole… Okay, training data, which is, in this case, it's, 60,000, I think.
Soon | NTU: Oh yeah, so it's going to be very, complicated, okay, taking into account the,
Soon | NTU: the number of training, iteration, and also the batch size. Okay, so I won't go to the detail. If you need to have more detail on this, Bobby, we can talk about it in
Soon | NTU: on a Saturday, huh?
Soon | NTU: If we have the time. Okay? So this is the… the structure of your neural network. Very simple, right? Okay? But the most challenging thing is, right, this is fixed.
Soon | NTU: because of your resolution of your input image, right? 28 by 28. So, during training, if your input is expected.
Soon | NTU: to be 28x28, okay? So when you roll out the train model in the production, you still have to have 28x28 in your environment, unless you do some kind of a resizing capability in your logic.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so that one, can talk about it later, okay? So this one, 128, is the first
Soon | NTU: Hidden layer.
Soon | NTU: number of neurons in the first hidden layer. Okay, so all these things have to match, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: And then finally, we will have an output layer of 10 neuron.
Soon | NTU: D.
Soon | NTU: And then, this one has to correspond to the, whatever architecture you have specified here. We have,
Soon | NTU: 1, 2, and… 3… Fully connected layer.
Soon | NTU: Yay.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this one will allow us to specify the activation function. We don't do it here.
Soon | NTU: Okay, because this is set up once, but this one we will call
Soon | NTU: During the training loop, right, over and over again, right? Let's remember our five-step, so-called training, the pattern, okay? So, first is to zeroize the gradient.
Soon | NTU: forward pass.
Soon | NTU: calculate the loss backward, and then optimize it to update the weight. Okay, so this is how the PyTorch training loop works, okay? So let's take a look at what the model architecture looks like. Okay, so let's just simply print out the model.
Soon | NTU: Because over here, we have created an instance of a model. So, by default, your bias will automate
Soon | NTU: Will be created, okay?
Soon | NTU: For each of the, the output
Soon | NTU: layer here, okay? So, now, now, one of the… the challenges of this…
Soon | NTU: Kind of a neural network is, especially for
Soon | NTU: CNN convolution neural network is,
Soon | NTU: There will be a lot of, weights that you…
Soon | NTU: potentially have to optimize, right? Going through all the different, forward paths and backward propagation in order to determine the, optimal weights, right? Okay? And also, maybe one of the things that you can do is also to
Soon | NTU: determine a… How many learnable widths are there as for this architecture?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so the one you can, fire also from this
Soon | NTU: Okay, so basically, there will be just simple mathematics, okay? 784 times 128 plus 128.
Soon | NTU: Plus.
Soon | NTU: 128 times 64 plus 64.
Soon | NTU: plus 64 times 10 plus 10, okay? So there will be a number which, I think it's about 100 over 1,000 for this architecture, okay? So, you need to
Soon | NTU: Do some, so-called fine-tuning, probably in your…
Soon | NTU: This is one of the,
Soon | NTU: things that you need to fine-tune, okay? So it potentially… your number of learnable weights that you need to tune is, let's say, in million
Soon | NTU: Then, hopefully, you have to think, you know.
Soon | NTU: Maybe that's one of the ways to…
Soon | NTU: Lower the resolution of your input.
Soon | NTU: image, okay? So that you do not have a high, number here. Okay, so when you go through all this.
Soon | NTU: Multiplier to determine the total number of weights, and then you have a very,
Soon | NTU: We have a smaller, number of weights to be trained, okay? So this is some of the things, okay?
Soon | NTU: For you to, take note, okay? So, now, of course, we need to specify the criteria. This is our loss function.
Soon | NTU: Right? And also the optimizer that we need to choose. Okay, so Adam is one of the optimizers. Okay, so just now, Jermaine has gone through a few
Soon | NTU: what auto-grade, and also, other, variations of,
Soon | NTU: optimizer. Okay, so this is when you can…
Soon | NTU: Specify the criteria optimizer, and also the learning rates.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so all these, Hyperparameter, which you need to tune also as part of your training loop.
Soon | NTU: Okay? Now, over here, Okay, so this is, Very simple.
Soon | NTU: five steps in your training loop, okay? So this is basically the train loader you have created just now, okay? So, this one will automatically take care of all the batching for you, okay? So, in this case, it's a batch of 64 images for each
Soon | NTU: So-called, training… loops, okay? So, one epoch is actually
Soon | NTU: contained a lot of, batches of 64, right? And then…
Soon | NTU: You will go through the same 5-step of initialize your gradient.
Soon | NTU: And then, this is the forward pass.
Soon | NTU: Calculate the loss.
Soon | NTU: Okay, you quantify the, you know, how much your prediction is, away from the actual value.
Soon | NTU: And then, this is a backward pass, where you go backward to We can't recompute your…
Soon | NTU: all the weights, right? And then this is where you update the weights.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: And then we need to… At every battery, we need to find out how much
Soon | NTU: is the so-called the accumulated loss, okay? Because we need to know, How is our trading loss?
Soon | NTU: Okay, over time.
Soon | NTU: So this won't actually print out.
Soon | NTU: the, training loss. Usually, because of this gradient descent algorithm, okay, you expect to see this, gradually decreasing, okay, as the number of,
Soon | NTU: the training loop, okay, goes on. Now, sometimes you may see this number going up and down, okay, so this is where you have to see whether you have something you need to tune in your learning rates.
Soon | NTU: King.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so here is the, code block for you to
Soon | NTU: do the prediction, okay? So, just now, over here.
Soon | NTU: We use a train loader, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, now, our test data… is…
Soon | NTU: It's kept in this test loader.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so, no, during prediction, you need to… disablists.
Soon | NTU: greeting.
Soon | NTU: computation.
Soon | NTU: Okay, because…
Soon | NTU: I think whenever you do something to this, PyTorch, you know, call the model, do something, there will be some kind of, gradient computation graph generated for you. Okay, so this is, not so…
Soon | NTU: not required when you're doing the inferencing, right? Because we only want to see
Soon | NTU: Whether our model is able to predict You know?
Soon | NTU: aligned to what we have in the test data, which the model have not seen during the training, okay? And then this is what we get, output.
Soon | NTU: And then, we need to do a lot of,
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is a very… I would say, very,
Soon | NTU: very compressed version of what, you know, you can do to actually take that
Soon | NTU: Okay, so basically, you're taking the…
Soon | NTU: Because the prediction here, right, will give you each of the image, they will have 10 numbers, right? Because we are using a softmax, log softmax, right? So, it will be a probability
Soon | NTU: Of, you know, a 0.10 number, of which the highest
Soon | NTU: Number, okay, will give you the,
Soon | NTU: will be the predicted, so-called DJ, okay?
Soon | NTU: So… And then this is the predicted value, and this is in the range of 0 to 9.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: And then?
Soon | NTU: you will… Okay, so the label size is…
Soon | NTU: The, number of labor, okay, that you have predicted.
Soon | NTU: And then, out of all this total number of predictions that the model have made, right, how many are correct?
Soon | NTU: Yeah, so this basically will tell you
Soon | NTU: Do a computation, okay, and this is how you get the, accuracy.
Soon | NTU: Okay, correct prediction versus The total prediction times 100%, you have a very high score of 95%.
Soon | NTU: Okay? So this is what the,
Soon | NTU: how we can use the PyTorch to do the, Training and also prediction.
Soon | NTU: 8.
Soon | NTU: Very simple, right?
Soon | NTU: Any question in the wheel?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I… So, so, just how earlier, right, you have the…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: F… I just try… I try to understand, because as I read the code and I read the comments, you are here. I'm not sure what I hear correctly.
Soon | NTU: Which line, you are not sure?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, there's actually the FC1, FC2, FC3. So, down there it says.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: This is what I'm looking at.
Soon | NTU: Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, let's create a simple neural network with two hidden layers. So in this case, like, FC1, 2, and 3.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, when I say two hidden layers, is it just fipping to 2, or 2 and 3?
Soon | NTU: Okay, when you look at the, circle number of layers in a neural network, right? Okay, you look at
Soon | NTU: The… how many layers have learner widths?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Amelia what?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Melissa, weird.
Soon | NTU: Hey, buddy.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Sorry, I don't understand.
Soon | NTU: Learnable wish.
Soon | NTU: It means either which step your… your model will… will learn… I mean, the parameter that you will learn.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Isn't, isn't, isn't the FC1, 2, and 3 defining the layers?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: No.
Soon | NTU: Okay, the learnable weights, right? Only… Okay?
Zac Ang: FC1 and FC2 are the weight of the layer only.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, I thought that, but I didn't, like, no one, like, differently.
Zac Ang: The FC3 they put, is the output layer, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, so down there, on the Commerce 2 hidden leaves, so it's actually, in this case.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: In this case, right, the code is only one hidden layer, not two lah, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, this is a very good example, okay? So, aligned to our… whatever we're trying to do for the, MNIST dataset now.
Soon | NTU: we have.
Soon | NTU: This is FC1.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Oh, these have C1.
Soon | NTU: I see too.
Soon | NTU: FC3.
Soon | NTU: Okay, now where are the weights residing?
Soon | NTU: Here, right?
Soon | NTU: healing.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, the lines are.
Soon | NTU: Yeah. The lights are the…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: beats.
Soon | NTU: where you find the lines and the widths are actually one line, one width associated with it, okay? So, if you see a architecture like this, okay, there were… this is a three-layer architecture.
Soon | NTU: You don't count this even though you have
Soon | NTU: sometimes you may draw this input layer as a circle. You don't say, oh, this is a circle.
Soon | NTU: 1, 2, 3, 4… no, you don't count like that.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yay.
Soon | NTU: you count which layer you have learnable weights, okay? So, now, you can do something like this, which, maybe I can see whether I have the luck.
Soon | NTU: Try to use AI to…
Soon | NTU: We still have some time, right?
Soon | NTU: Because, Titanic dataset is, much, easier. Okay, we can… try to… Let's see… Oh, queen.
Soon | NTU: Duh.
Soon | NTU: Don't, the number of parameter in the network, okay? So…
Soon | NTU: Okay, so… This is stoked up.
Soon | NTU: And, let me see what I can…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Well, I really need to add a video. The sound of my house has powered has blacked out. I need to buy a video to read this again.
Soon | NTU: finger… respectifa.
Soon | NTU: Beats.
Soon | NTU: Shouldn't we initially, yeah.
germayne: Soon, actually, I think there should be… there should be a library. Last time, I used to use a library to print the number of parameters on. I, I need to find it again.
germayne: But you don't need to manually do this. There's actually a library to do it. Is that the question from Noel? Like, how many parameters you want to.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: No, no, my question was trying to understand, like, because this cell, right, he actually builds the network, so I want to understand, like.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: You know, when you say two hidden layers, which two hidden layers is he talking about? Is it the 1 and 2, or is it… I thought it was 2 and 3.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But it seems I'm wrong, so it's like 1 and 2, but 3 is the output, I think.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Based on the comments on the code.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So the two here is actually FC1 and FC2 lah.
germayne: No, but they're all parameters. So, all of them, the last one, they also need to learn what?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Awful.
germayne: If your question is, what is the categorization of the hidden layer, usually they call it the middle two, except the outside one, but you're finding…
germayne: No, no, no, but the final matrix is also parameters, just that people don't call it hidden layer.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Oh…
germayne: It's just a… it's just a notation thing.
germayne: layer is also a W, right?
germayne: So, so, it's.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Dude, you're.
germayne: You still have to learn, you still have to learn it.
germayne: If there's your.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, I was trying to learn the… the…
germayne: the court.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: The layer, yeah.
germayne: Yeah.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so, so our.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Maybe, maybe the, the things at the code here is all numbers, so I was trying to understand what the numbers are, you know, because it's 128, 64, 64, 10, and… yeah, what, why is, why is 64, why is 10, why is 128?
Soon | NTU: It's, 128 times 784 plus 128, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Huh.
Soon | NTU: you get total number of learner per wage for FC1.
Soon | NTU: Okay, and then you calculate the FC2, a learnable weight is 64 times 128 plus 64, you get another number, okay, and then likewise for FC3, you get another number. So you add up these three numbers, right? It'll give you 109386.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But all these numbers are not input by you, by the, by you, right, or things like that, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I don't think that number…
Soon | NTU: mention is,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mentioned, I know laid today, but to me, that's a.
Soon | NTU: To be sizes.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: picture.
Soon | NTU: Hyperparameter for you to tune.
Soon | NTU: if you're not happy with 128, maybe 168 sounds better, you know?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, right, 128 then. I mean, that's the purpose of all the calculation, right? Calculate W, right? Isn't it?
Soon | NTU: You, you, you can, like, 128, but if you change here, you have to change here also, lah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, lah. But how do you arrive at 128, or it's just when… in this example, in this far example, it's just since. That doesn't matter lah.
germayne: So it's a permit, it's a permit.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: It's just, yeah, it's a, it's a…
germayne: And rule of thumb… rule of thumb is 2 to the power of… 2 to the power of something. You notice it's all in 2 to the power of something.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, I really like.
germayne: Yes, that's what the rule of thumb people used to do, lah.
Soon | NTU: Also for the batch size, right,
Soon | NTU: Rule of tongue is a multiple of, 32.
Soon | NTU: Because I think I read somewhere it's because of the way the GPU is designed. I think there.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Oh…
Soon | NTU: concept map. So, if you have something designed in multiple 32, then you will have
Soon | NTU: can leverage on the power of the GPU better, you know, rather than.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, okay. Yeah, that's right, because the numbers, I see the numbers are not very clear. That's why I'm asking, like,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: That's the second question. I think all the numbers here was like… because you're talking about… we've been talking about W and everything, so I was like, oh, is that the way you calculate? Just sometimes the W, it's like, alright.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay. Okay.
Soon | NTU: Any more questions from others?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, the other thing, now that I see ePorch, what does ePorch mean? Does it… is it, like, faux?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Is it, like, 4? You do 5 times 4?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Oh, is it.
Soon | NTU: One epoch is equivalent to one training iteration, okay?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Are we seeing?
Soon | NTU: Eat.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Epo is the iteration,
Soon | NTU: The… maybe batch… the batching, the chunk, right, is equivalent to your…
Soon | NTU: Your… your cross-validation concept. We actually chop it into 5 parts, right?
Soon | NTU: Whereas this one is, .
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, so the training starts, like, the full, like, you do, like, how many, how many times you run, then…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Come back again. I mean, the concept, like…
Soon | NTU: For performance reasons lah, okay? Rather than loading, 60,000 images all at once, okay?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
Soon | NTU: And you only get one,
Soon | NTU: iteration. Okay, why not you do it in patches?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
Soon | NTU: example.
Soon | NTU: images.
germayne: I think for the training loop, if you guys want Saturday, I can talk about it.
germayne: Yeah, I don'.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because I was just thinking, how does it do, like, you know, training and validation, you know, for neural networks?
germayne: No, no, no, no, you're cons… no, no, it's two different things. So the training loop, right, relates to what I talked about just now for the updates of the weights.
germayne: Right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: forward and backward.
germayne: Yes, exactly. So then the question to you is how many times must I do forward and backward? That is where the training loop affects it. It has nothing to do with the validation.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay…
germayne: I can talk about it on Saturday.
germayne: No, no.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: That's a…
germayne: But now does it answer?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, yeah, that's not that powerful answer I was thinking what I said, what?
germayne: No, because I… I didn't talk about…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: teary.
germayne: No, I didn't talk about it, I didn't talk about it. So, the question mark here is, how many times must I go forward and backward?
germayne: That… that is determined by the training loop, that is determined by your batch size, that influences how many iterations, and that…
germayne: would tell you there is one full epoch in terms of how many iterations, that's why I put a formula there. It's just your total data size divided by batch size, that's the total number of iterations.
germayne: There's one epoch. So I'll talk about that maybe in detail on Saturday, I guess.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, okay, okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Wow.
Soon | NTU: And also, sometimes your batch size, right, is not… let's say your 60,000 training data size, if you divide it by 64, right, okay, you may come up with some, end up with some residual in the last batch. May not be equivalent to 64.
Soon | NTU: Maybe, only 10 record.
Soon | NTU: Oh, 7 record.
Soon | NTU: Again, so this is.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, are all these that we talked about, all these are, like, hyperparameters that we… that we need to set, control, and do, or is it…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, try error, the way I see it.
Soon | NTU: Yes, bedside is also one of the, hyperparameters.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Right, yeah, you got to, yeah, tune here and there, then it's hyperparameter lah, so you keep changing the thing lah.
Soon | NTU: Yes, yes.
Soon | NTU: Okay? So…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So is that… so now that I… I thought I mentioned about cross-validation, so is that… is the idea of cross-validation applicable for neural networks?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I'm assuming it does lah, but… That su…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: clear my head. It does, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: You know, testing, cross-validation.
germayne: Yes, yes, yes, awesome.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
germayne: But, good question, good question. Everything we thought is all linked, it's not like suddenly.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, that's why, yeah, yeah, but that's what I'm trying to find, like, for different models, like, when is… where is the… where do you, like, you know, do the forwarding? Or is this…
Soon | NTU: At the same time.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean.
Soon | NTU: We have batch, we have cross-validation, so that will make the whole thing very complicated. Now, the next example data set… Thank you.
Soon | NTU: Yeah, welcome. The next example dataset is the Titanic, so we are going back to this. So, we have already seen how we use a linear regression, right?
Soon | NTU: again, to do prediction after, training using the Titanic dataset. Okay, so…
Soon | NTU: Everything looks the same, okay, because this is a…
Soon | NTU: a classification, so-called, model, right? We want to train a deep learning model to make prediction
Soon | NTU: whether survive or not survive, right? So there's actually no different from our classification model that we have built, okay, earlier on, using the logistic regression, right? Right? And also the K&N, right? Now.
Soon | NTU: The only difference is you have to import the relevant library for PyTorch.
Soon | NTU: Right? Okay. Especially this data loader and the data set, right? So, we will leverage on this, ability to do batching, right? All this capability. Otherwise, you will have to do this manually.
Soon | NTU: Right? Without all these utility classes, right? You have to do all these patches manually, right? Now, so…
Soon | NTU: the usual import load data set, because Titanic is a Building dataset of the…
Soon | NTU: One of the viewing data sets of a Seabourn library.
Soon | NTU: Right? So this one, you should be very familiar.
Soon | NTU: Some missing value here and there, and we have,
Soon | NTU: Shortlisted some of the field, some of the features for our illustration, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay? So… I believe you should know what's the implication of doing this, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so I think Python… It can be very, struggle, very…
Soon | NTU: complicated, right? If you are not, sure of this concept call, you know, whether is it in place, update, in place, whatever, you know, versus something you are doing outside the actual data frame itself, okay? So now we are doing everything in place, so whatever thing we do, imputation, drop.
Soon | NTU: missing, data, okay? It is all directly updating our data frame, which is called data. It's already a copy of this Titanic data frame, so the original data frame is intact.
Soon | NTU: unchangen.
Soon | NTU: And then we'll go through the usual pre-processing step to Remove.
Soon | NTU: This target from our feature, and then put our…
Soon | NTU: label column as Y, right? We need to use the consistent naming convention. And then, these are the numeric feature and the categorical feature we have in the Titanic dataset.
Soon | NTU: Right? Because the pre-processing step would be different.
Soon | NTU: If your data types are different, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this one you should be very familiar.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: And then… We will go through the pre-processing
Soon | NTU: Train test split, 80%. Training data, 20%, testing data.
Soon | NTU: put aside.
Soon | NTU: fall.
Soon | NTU: Testing the train model, again.
Soon | NTU: No.
Soon | NTU: This is the… Part where you need to do.
Soon | NTU: Okay, in order to make use of the PyTorch library, right?
Soon | NTU: if you want to retain the original WhatNumPy array, or this will not work, okay, when you want to use a PyTorch library. So you need to convert everything into a PyTorch floating-point 32-bit, right?
Soon | NTU: So that you have To create another version of the training test
Soon | NTU: training and testing data, okay, in, tensor data type.
Soon | NTU: Okay?
Soon | NTU: And then, with this, we'll continue to build your training data and test data in the PyTorch way.
Soon | NTU: Right? Slightly different from the SK learned way of, training, right?
Soon | NTU: And then… now…
Soon | NTU: In this Jupyter notebook, right, you have never seen that we need to move your model or your data to some GPU or whatever.
Soon | NTU: MPS if you're using a MacBook, right? Now, the reason is, this is a very simple
Soon | NTU: illustration, simple example. We do not need a GPU.
Soon | NTU: Right? So…
Soon | NTU: That's why we did not include the tool device kind of a statement to move your tensor to your
Soon | NTU: GPU.
Soon | NTU: During training and during the inference.
Soon | NTU: Right? Okay, so we just want to make the code clean, okay?
Soon | NTU: But if you're dealing with a huge dataset, which we'll see on Thursday, right, there will be a lot of tool device, right? You're moving a lot of your training data over to the GPU during training, okay? So now.
Soon | NTU: we need to define our Titanic, so-called neural network class, Right.
Soon | NTU: So this is a very standard way of,
Soon | NTU: for you to specify the architecture of your neural network, okay? In this case, for your Titanic dataset.
Soon | NTU: quite similar, right? The only difference is, instead of hard-coding the value.
Soon | NTU: We put it in the, parameters.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: So that means when you quit.
Soon | NTU: And… copy of your Titanic neural network, right? You have to specify all your
Soon | NTU: parameters, okay? So, of course, next, we have to make sure that we special artists?
Soon | NTU: you can also do it, over here, right? But usually we will have, this is, well documented, because if you put the T like this, right.
Soon | NTU: people will not know, hey, what is this second parameter? What does it mean, right? So usually the way we do it is hidden size 13, output size 1, and then we use the variable name. Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: The earlier I'm able to do something like this, then…
Soon | NTU: Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yes.
Soon | NTU: to make your boat more, reusable, okay? Anyone can do. So you can freely, freely gonna fine-tune, oh, if I can…
Soon | NTU: do a for next loop, right? Testing the different hidden sites. You can do it if you have already packaged your code like this.
Soon | NTU: Right? If you hard-code, then not possible. Okay? So, likewise, we need to create our loss function.
Soon | NTU: right, which required criteria, and then the optimizer, in this case, learning rate is 0.001. Okay, so now, the loss function is, binary cross, entropy, because we are making,
Soon | NTU: prediction of 2 value, right? 0 and 1.
Soon | NTU: So it's a binary, value in your wine.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: And then this is also… Can you see the… Okay.
Soon | NTU: The five steps.
Soon | NTU: Okay?
Soon | NTU: So, of course, we need to do a lot of, reshaping, right?
Soon | NTU: But this is a simpler, right, because of the batch size, right?
Soon | NTU: And then, we will predict, this is a forward pass.
Soon | NTU: Calculate the loss.
Soon | NTU: So, 1, 2… 3, 4, 5, right?
Soon | NTU: And then, at every 20 epoch, you print out the loss Okay, the training lost.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so I think this is,
Soon | NTU: This is not the average, so you may probably can fine-tune this
Soon | NTU: Alright, this is only the loss of the last batch, right? Okay, so as you can see, the number actually go up and down, right?
Soon | NTU: Probably, I think, right, because of this, lost stock item here.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so…
Soon | NTU: And then, this is the code block for making the prediction. As before, we need to disable the,
Soon | NTU: gradient calculation.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: So there is a lot of documentation here to explain to you the reason why we always do this during the prediction stage, right? When we have predictions need to be made, right, we will have to make use of the test loader
Soon | NTU: Because your density, like, it's kept here. And then…
Soon | NTU: This is to compare, right? Make the prediction. Your output now contain your prediction value.
Soon | NTU: King.
Soon | NTU: In the probabilities, huh?
Soon | NTU: Okay? But then, because this is… the label have to be in 120, right? 1 or 0, in order to compare it with the…
Soon | NTU: Actual value in your… You know, test set.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this one basically is to… Expand all this label to…
Soon | NTU: all these predictions, 0, 1, 1, 0, and so on, they accumulated into this variable, this array, this list called the Y prediction, okay? So, now you have
Soon | NTU: the complete Y prediction value for, I think, about 10,000 value, because the test dataset is about…
Soon | NTU: sorry, not 10,000, it's, 10,000 is for the MNIS dataset, okay? So this is the size of your…
Soon | NTU: Test data.
Soon | NTU: And then you have to calculate your… The different, classification metrics.
Soon | NTU: Right? And then you have this… Classification metrics are printed here.
Soon | NTU: So… 0.62… F1 score.
Soon | NTU: Is it better than the linear regression? Can you still recall?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so basically, yeah.
Gwendalynn Lim: Supposed to be .85.
Soon | NTU: Sorry?
Gwendalynn Lim: Is… is… it's no, right?
Soon | NTU: to be pointed.
Gwendalynn Lim: 85?
Soon | NTU: Calling 85… What do you mean?
Gwendalynn Lim: So, is it… I thought that a classical linear regression, the accepted towards 1 is 0.85 and up.
Soon | NTU: The linear regression, I… can't remember what we score.
Soon | NTU: Okay?
Gwendalynn Lim: Have a look at that one.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so… so these are the score…
Soon | NTU: 0.74… not very… not very high, right, accuracy.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so… They mean that there are a lot of things that we need to fine-tune for this model.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Maybe because you dropped a lot of, empty rows, so… I don't know.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: And we draw a law, you draw a law.
Soon | NTU: We do not have a lot of empty rows. Anyway, our data set is very small.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
Soon | NTU: Yeah, so that is, I think, one of the reasons why this neural network is very, data hungry, right? So the more data, the merrier for training a neural network.
Soon | NTU: It is Sony… 1,000, 5,000, you know, may not be able to,
Soon | NTU: Meet the, you know, the hung…
Soon | NTU: the hunger of the neural network. Okay, so that is the,
Soon | NTU: what we have, for the, Jupyter Notebook.
Soon | NTU: on the PyTorch, right?
Soon | NTU: Any other questions from,
Soon | NTU: Yeah, yeah, there's some, very good note from Philip, yeah.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we also have to take into account the last patch, right? Sometimes the last patch may
Soon | NTU: every batch is 64, only the last patch may be only 10 records, okay? So, you may have, can choose to ignore the last batch, okay? So, I think there is a parameter here.
Soon | NTU: I'm not sure whether it is you.
Soon | NTU: Okay, drop loss.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so default is false. So if your last batch, because of some…
Soon | NTU: The reason, you know, every batch size is 64, last one only 5 records, okay? You may set this drop last to true, so that your last
Soon | NTU: Patch will not be, processor.
Soon | NTU: In your training group.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so that's all for this, Jupyter Notebook.
Soon | NTU: session.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so… Back to you, Jubin.
germayne: Hmm, okay, thank you, thank you soon.
germayne: Okay, so you guys can see there's actually two very drastic areas, right? One is, I think, in terms of understanding, and another one is how to write the pipeline.
germayne: I think there are a lot of new ones in writing the pipeline. Don't think we can complete, but I think the best is to still explore how people write it first, right?
germayne: And I think that one you can gain through experience.
germayne: Okay? So… yeah.
germayne: Okay, I think the missing thing probably is just the training loop. I think we can spend some time talking about it more on Saturday. So, Saturday, right, we will end the Kaggle competition. So, what this means is that the top X
germayne: winner will need to present and share their solution. So hopefully that doesn't deter you from winning. I mean, you guys will get prizes. There'll be prizes.
germayne: So…
germayne: I mean, we will discuss on what are the interesting things. I'm sure you guys will want to know what people are doing, right? Correct? So, it's not like a presentation per se, but we'll just share, like, each team will just need to share. But I think, for me, I can spend some time collecting things to go through, so I think the training loop will be one of them. Yeah, I can talk about that on…
germayne: On Saturday, not a problem.
germayne: Okay, I think today we… actually pretty good. I think we went, we… we completed this on time, actually.
germayne: Fantastic. Yeah, deep topic, and we finish on time.
germayne: After this module, if you guys are still very keen in going deeper, there are really a lot of resources. You can either take some
germayne: causes from Stanford, or you can also take Andrew Erng's Deep Learning Specialization. I think those would
germayne: would give more nuance.
germayne: Okay, so what do you guys learn today?
germayne: Only got one parti… only got one participant.
germayne: Where's, where's everyone?
germayne: Wait, did I do something wrong?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: bus.
germayne: Huh?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: You're too fast.
germayne: Oh, oh, sorry, sorry, wait, am I supposed to go previously, or what?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: No, no, no.
germayne: Oh, just scan, just scan, okay, okay, got it, got it, got it.
germayne: Pay off her. Apologize for that.
germayne: Okay, yes, yes.
germayne: Yeah, so I think the, the, the gradient descent, yeah, we talk a lot about that.
germayne: PyTorch, yes, that's the library.
germayne: Yeah, been a while, right? Been a while since we've seen the application of
germayne: Differentiating. You're not just differentiating for fun, right?
germayne: I think that's what I like about… about data science. I think there's a lot of application that
germayne: Has a lot of utility based on what you learn in school.
germayne: Alright.
germayne: Okay, so yeah, so I think this is a very good intro.
germayne: And… yeah, and backboard location, yes, yes.
germayne: Okay, okay, okay, let's continue.
germayne: So, which part do you think is the most challenging for you today?
germayne: Which portion?
germayne: Which segment? Actually, we only have a few key segments.
germayne: the value of W.
germayne: Value of W,
germayne: I think… I think the… the… the easy way to really take away the W is you just think of it like a… it's just a matrix.
germayne: Which is why I think, if you saw in the notebook, Sun just says you take the… the in multiplied by the R, right? That's basically just the size of the matrix.
germayne: It's just the row and the column. It's just the row and column size. So, if your row is N and your column is M, the total number of elements in the matrix is n times n, right? That is the size of the matrix. And that is the number of parameters for that specific layer.
germayne: And of course, I omitted the bias.
germayne: You need to include the bias as well, but… yeah.
germayne: Zach's question is challenging.
germayne: Wait, what did Zach ask that was challenging?
Zac Ang: I forget what I asked Radi, so I don't know what he's talking about.
germayne: Okay, so, for… for Thursday, right?
germayne: We won't be doing a lot of, like, math.
germayne: But Thursday will be tricky if you are not very comfortable with
germayne: Matrix that is more than 2, 2, 3 dimensions.
germayne: So I'm going to tell you guys that first.
germayne: Okay, so, in Module 1, you guys probably learned about NumPy, right?
germayne: So, if you think about NumPy as a matrix, your matrix can be more than three-dimensional.
germayne: We need to… we will need to…
germayne: Be a bit comfortable with that, okay?
germayne: Yeah, I hope everything's okay for Noel. I hope everything's okay for your blackout.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, some… some video gone. Then, I think you mentioned about…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: non-linerity, when I, when I think about doing Blackout, when I came back, or this one, I didn't, I didn't hear. So, yeah, so I went
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I think we… yeah…
germayne: the NTU's video is being shared, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, yeah.
germayne: I mean, I think…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I'll do. Look at that,
germayne: Josiah, no? Noah?
germayne: Ben, I think…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: It's been shared, no, I think. The last few weeks, I think it was shared.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, I think…
Jagatheeswaran Rajagurunathan: The recordings, mah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: There's a recordings folder, which you can see, yeah.
Edwin Yap: Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So far, it's up to 3.7, 3.6.
germayne: Yeah, that's the latest, then I think with this one, probably, they'll upload it.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, so Poppy has to wait for that one.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But I think that time when it broke out when, blacked out when there was a lot of…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Exciting thing, you're talking about, the discussion on forward or backward, whatever, yeah.
germayne: Yeah, that's okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I was like.
germayne: No, no, don't worry, Alex.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: And so, yeah.
germayne: Don't worry, don't worry. I will upload the annotated notes.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: But don't worry, don't worry, yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But because you talk so much about W, that I… my intuition was that during the coding, right, we had to have some sort of sense of W, you see.
germayne: W.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Who's your opponent.
germayne: Maritos.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because he said, wait, Mars, I was like, wait, wait, wait, miss one.
germayne: The same is the same. It's all synonym weight, parameters is the same.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Oh… Okay, okay, okay. I thought it's two different values, I had to go and calculate.
germayne: No, no, you don't have to calculate either to calculate.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Basically, what you mean is, like, you don't have to spend a lot of… crack your brain to find that value, lah, that's what you're trying to say, right? It's just a simple mathematical calculation.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: After the, yeah, now we talk about it, I don't.
germayne: Hmm.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so what, what, what, what, what is the… what is, what went well?
germayne: For you guys.
germayne: So what, what is a good, what was a good takeaway?
germayne: Today.
germayne: For different people.
Edwin Yap: Hi, Jamin, I've been here.
germayne: Hmm, yes, yes, Erin.
Edwin Yap: Yeah, to me, I think what went well, I think I'll just use words.
Edwin Yap: to explain, because just now, I think you purposely kept some empty space. I think it's really good, even though math is…
Edwin Yap: tough to me, because that's what I wrote, but I think by you writing down and explaining, right, I think it gives me a better picture. I'm a very visual person, so after you wrote, I may not really understand the formula, however, but after seeing you writing down, I have some intuition, okay, where are we heading towards? So I think it's really good that you have the empty space for
Edwin Yap: the explanation. So, this one, I'll give it to you. Yeah, that's about.
germayne: Okay, okay, thanks. Thanks, Erwin. So, means I can add more empty spaces for the next few lessons.
germayne: Okay, bye, bye.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But I don't… I don't like the platter beside it, because it's sort of a block.
germayne: Whoa.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: That one is, like, my pen,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I know, I know, I thought it could be somewhere else, but I was like, oh, you know, you do it there, talk of it,
germayne: Okay, okay, I think I can, I think I, I think I can, I can shift it, I can shift it, okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
germayne: I guess.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: It's always in the view, then you move our A cover already, then an A. Okay.
germayne: Okay, I think I got the feedback. I move it to the top.
germayne: Okay, okay, so I think implementing looks easier than expected. Wow, who says this?
germayne: So, the, the funding.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I see what, I see one.
germayne: Oh.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, of course, because neural levels tend to be very difficult to explain, but when I look at another one, oh, it's just 3 lines only, oh, okay, it's just the…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: values, the code wasn't well… the Italian one was easier to understand, but I think the earlier one was harder to understand.
germayne: It's supposed to work.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: relate.
germayne: It's supposed to be easier, yeah, yeah. I mean, the point of a library is to take away the pinpoint. You don't need to go and do the manual calculation yourself. It's all handled.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: But yes, I think… I think the advice is just take more time to go through this, if needed. If, let's say, you're not using it, it might… you will just forget, but…
germayne: Take, take more, take more time to digest this.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: What about that? You know, on Saturday, you show us the configuration file and all the…
germayne: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, so you remember that, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, then I was saying, how come you all never talk about, about that at all? No, so…
germayne: So, that we did, right? I think soon when.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, I mean, for today's lesson, I mean, for today's lesson.
germayne: Or, no lah, today's lesson is not production level, what?
germayne: You know, I just only showed that in the YAML, you can… now you understand why I got the thing to configure, right? Now you guys understand the content, right? The context.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because I find that you've got so many parameters, like, whoa, without… like, when you, like, some of that code, like, well, I cannot see anything, or I look at the numbers, I don't understand a single thing, so I… I mean, like, I had to go and search for it, so…
germayne: Wait, so, only you got 4 people here, the rest all went back home ready, is it?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Like, talking at the moment, right? But a lot of…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: You're gonna have, like, a lot of stuff to…
germayne: Yeah, so there will be 4 lessons on neural network. The next 3 is also the same.
germayne: Just on different domain.
germayne: Yeah?
germayne: Yes, yes, yes, there are some things here that I didn't take time to go into the, the, the, the, the…
germayne: like, the multiplication, for example, so that one you can just revisit on your own. If you don't know, you can ask me.
germayne: Okay, so I think… I think that's all. On Thursday, we will go through the neural network, but done on images, so we are going to go into computer vision.
germayne: Okay? So, I don't think… definitely less math, for sure less math.
germayne: But if you do happen to write, you know, if you do have a chance to go into the backpropagation for the computer vision one, I can guarantee you, very complex, okay? But we won't be going through that, so don't worry, we'll just be talking about application on images, okay?
germayne: Okay? So this is actually going to be very, very simple. I think tomorrow's class is gonna be… sorry, no, tomorrow's… Thursday is going to be easy. Okay? So, I think that's all for today. Thank you, thank you, everyone.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Beautiful.
germayne: Good evening, yep, thank you, thank you, thank you everyone.
Zac Ang: one.
germayne: Yeah?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Hi.
germayne: See you guys. See you guys on Thursday. Yeah? Bye-bye, bye-bye.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I…
germayne: Bye-bye. I think some people got questions can stay back, yep.
Edwin Yap: Yeah, I think for mine, it's quite straightforward. So, Jamin, regarding to the environment we have to create.
Edwin Yap: the DAR environment, right, if the torch, the PyTorch, if having issue… what did Sun mention, sorry, I think I missed that.
germayne: Let me see.
Soon | NTU: Yeah, it's a DL environment.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, you need to hunt down.
Soon | NTU: Claudia Owens.
Soon | NTU: From this lesson onwards.
Edwin Yap: First, I think I'm stuck at the…
Edwin Yap: talk. I'm trying to download, I restarted, let me try again. If cannot, then I'll ask on Thursday.
Edwin Yap: Thanks.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay. Well, Sula's got a question. Kendra, you got question, right?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yes, actually, I think facing the problem, it's a common problem, and I'm not sure where is my, like, blind spot for that, because
Chieh Cheng Lai: every time I attend the machine learning class, and then, for example, this time we're doing the project, but I will not get the… I mean, I will not get the optimized, outcome, and then each time like that, and then, I also not sure what's the problem going… I mean, what's wrong on me.
Chieh Cheng Lai: So, that's why I keep puzzling. Even I attend few classes, I mean, the results come up to be the same.
germayne: Oh, you mean… wait, what's the result? Sorry, what was the result?
Chieh Cheng Lai: I mean, I mean, the result, for example, last time, I remember I attended one of the many other courses on the machine learning, quite a few years ago, and then, the predicted result is, very bad, and then, maybe 60 or 70%, and then, after that.
Chieh Cheng Lai: I don't know what is going on, and some… some of them can… I mean, some of my, classmates can do better, and I have no idea on that.
germayne: Hmm.
Chieh Cheng Lai: And then, this comment is keep coming on, and then, I'm not too sure, what I have been missing, or things I didn't notice.
Chieh Cheng Lai: So, this will be a… I think this will be a problem for me in the long term, if I continue it this way.
germayne: Okay, then, maybe just want to understand, when you say the prediction was not very good.
germayne: Was it on something? Kaggle or something, is it?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Kegel, Kaggle, this, this is first time I tried, yeah, the Kaggle, actually, for example, first try, the first initial I tried, I only get, the RMSEs quite bad, I mean.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Even the R-squared also back, R-squared is only 77%. The second times I tried the R-square, I remember it's 93, but it's not good enough in the competition now.
germayne: Soon.
Chieh Cheng Lai: from there, I am… because… I able to get,
Chieh Cheng Lai: 93% because I asked, AI, place on my model, and then I want to try another method to see what's their improvement, then they suggest me on deck. But…
Chieh Cheng Lai: This one, I also realized that, am I too… if this is the case, I'm too dependent on the AIRD.
germayne: Hmm.
Chieh Cheng Lai: So, I properly, have… do not have my own thinking, this, like.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yeah, so…
germayne: So, right, so maybe back to the general question, right? I think what you ask is very general, so very hard to give you this advice, but the thing about data science is that you realize is that there's a lot of
germayne: trial and error. You realize? Basically, you need to try. You need to try something which you do not know whether it will work or not. You realize this is the common pattern, right?
Chieh Cheng Lai: young.
germayne: Data science.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yeah, this is the bro… this is the issue, the main issue for me, because I am not sure,
Chieh Cheng Lai: How to try out, and then try what on that.
germayne: Alright.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yeah.
germayne: Alright, correct. So, I think there's many, many areas lah. I think one is…
germayne: Okay, so firstly, we established that data science has a lot of things to try. Now, what to try? So, I think this really tests you on
germayne: maybe firstly, if you think about it, it's really asking the right question. So think about, like, what you want to explore. So it's actually back to the EDA also, right? Like.
germayne: when you explore a data, what are some of the questions that you want to try to answer? This one you need to come up… you need to come up with the hypothesis, and usually it's with relation to what is it that you're trying to solve.
germayne: You see? So…
germayne: very hard to give you, like, a guideline that will be, like, okay, this… you're just going to apply this, because the… I think the problem with data science is that… or rather, the challenge with data science is that it's not,
germayne: Here we are.
germayne: Sorry, sorry, we are, yeah, we are.
germayne: G.
germayne: thing that we… Stop.